<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Daily Reading</title>
  <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
  <link>https://newheights.org</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

  <item>
    <title>March 1</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.3.NIV">Numbers 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.4.NIV">Numbers 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.21.NIV">Proverbs 10:21</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 3 - It's easy to get lost in who's related to whom and ask why this person mentioned. Here's a helpful-hint: the story to the original audience was literally seen as their wilderness travel log heading into the Promised Land of Israel. It was a time to trust God and set-up structured worship and healthy relationships to help walk with God once they arrived.</p>
        <p>Numbers 4 - When you read about the Sons of Aaron, Kohath, or their descendents (or the duties of Levites) a helpful hint is this simply means "Priest"- or the guys who facilitate worship in the Tent of Meeting. There's subtle differences between Levites and priests; all priests are Levites, but not all Levites are priests. They are preparing to establish worship, and the priests had to come from this tribe of Levi.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar1">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?61</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>


  <item>
    <title>March 2</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.5.NIV">Numbers 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.6.NIV">Numbers 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.34.1-7.NIV">Psalm 34:1-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.22.NIV">Proverbs 10:22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MRK.16.NIV">Mark 16</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 5-6 - Chapter 5 is tough for modern readers. Keep in mind two things- first, this was a communal society. The thought was if someone is contagious or stealing, then everyone in the community gets hurt. Second, this culture uses symbols to reflect reality. Notice how chapter 6 ends with a blessing from the priests. This verse becomes so powerful it becomes the first verse of Psalm 67.</p>
        <p>Psalm 34:1-7 - This style of psalm is really cool, it's structured in such a way that every line begins with the next letter of the original language's alphabet. Psalm 34 was also a Psalm heavily referenced in the New Testament.</p>
        <p>Mark 16 - Your Bible may say the end of this chapter wasn't in the earliest manuscripts. This is one of the few verses where we're not sure if this was added to the original Manuscript after the fact. However, the first eight verses are 100% valid, no debate. Jesus defeated death, and we live in light of that. And the rest of the chapter (whether it was originally there or not) doesn't impact our theology or understanding of Jesus.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar2">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?62</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>March 3</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XIb_dCIxzr0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.7.NIV">Numbers 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.8.NIV">Numbers 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.34.8-14.NIV">Psalm 34:8-14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.23.NIV">Proverbs 10:23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.1.NIV">Luke 1</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 7-8 - Numbers runs parallel with sections of Exodus & Leviticus, so we get a review of the construction of the Tabernacle/Tent of Meeting. The preceding chapters show who facilitates worship, this chapter shows where worship happens.</p>
        <p>Psalm 34:8-14 - A noteworthy verse is, "Taste and see that the LORD is good". This line is poetically inviting us to experience God's goodness; it's not about just knowing it, but it's an opportunity for us to experience and sense it.</p>
        <p>Luke 1 - This is Luke's verified eye-witness account of Jesus' life. Luke is the Apostle Paul's co-worker, and he's writing to someone very prominent (Theophilus), to specifically detail Jesus' life. These two miraculous birth announcements begin building up anticipation for the Promised King who saves the world (who's promised in the Old Testament) and the prophet who announces His coming (picture a herald announcing a king). This will be Jesus and John the Baptist, and they are the fulfillment of these long anticipated promises.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar3">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?63</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>March 4</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.9.NIV">Numbers 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.10.NIV">Numbers 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.34.15-22.NIV">Psalm 34:15-22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.24-25.NIV">Proverbs 10:24-25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.2.NIV">Luke 2</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 9-10 - We see the second celebration of the Passover (the most important holiday for Israel). It commemorates God redeeming Israel from slavery in Egypt. Afterwards everyone packs up camp and leaves after staying for a year. The trumpets are an audible call for the millions of people to start moving in an organized fashion.</p>
        <p>Psalm 34:15-22 - The poem starts with personal praise, but leads to an invitation for others. It's a poignant reminder that when we praise God it encourages others to worship Him.</p>
        <p>Luke 2 - The shepherds were first to praise, witness, and proclaim Jesus, demonstrating God's concern for outcasts because shepherds weren't highly honored in the 1st century. We also learn Jesus was born into a poor family, and we know this because offering doves in the Temple was an allowance for those who couldn't afford the typical sacrifice.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar4">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?64</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>March 5</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.11.NIV">Numbers 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.12.NIV">Numbers 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.35.1-10.NIV">Psalm 35:1-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.26.NIV">Proverbs 10:26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.3.NIV">Luke 3</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 11-12 - The next movement in the book gives three complaints of the people while traveling. They complain about food, water, and Moses' leadership; they even wish to return to Egypt... back to slavery! It's similar to us; we often forget God's faithfulness, and begin complaining.</p>
        <p>Psalm 35:1-10 - This is a "Lament" Psalm. It's a poem of mourning. It's amazing, because crying out to God leads to joy at the end of the Psalm.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 10:26 - Vinegar and smoke were seen as unpleasant; the comparison reveals laziness is also unpleasant.</p>
        <p>Luke 3 -  Luke continues demonstrating Jesus is the Promised King. Whether it's John, God the Father, or the genealogy linking Jesus to David, Luke is teaching us that Jesus is King. Also, Luke links Jesus' lineage to Adam, showing Jesus' connection to humanity. God humbled Himself to be one of us.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar5">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?65</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>March 6</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.13.NIV">Numbers 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.14.NIV">Numbers 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.35.11-16.NIV">Psalm 35:11-16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.27-28.NIV">Proverbs 10:27-28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.4.NIV">Luke 4</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 13 - This is a hinge point for the whole book of Numbers. God sends twelve spies (one from each tribe) out into the Promised Land of Israel. The ten spies return and call the people already in the land Nephilim, which in the original language, means "fallen ones" and contains the idea of violent warriors. The other two spies are calling for people to trust God because He led them out of Egypt- the most powerful empire in the world at the time. The two spies remind the people that they can trust God no matter what comes their way. </p>
        <p>Luke 4 - This is the beginning of Jesus' public ministry. He begins by being tempted by the devil. His temptation shows us that He can relate to us when we're tempted and gives us an example of persevering through temptation. See Hebrews 4:15 to read more about it.  </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar6">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?66</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 7</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.15.NIV">Numbers 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.16.NIV">Numbers 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.29-30.NIV">Proverbs 10:29-30</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 15 - Numbers is divided by narratives of travelling, and then in between those stories, teaching sections of the Instructions from the Lord. Remember It's a travel log. Think of parents on a roadtrip laying down some guidelines for their kids.</p>
        <p>Numbers 16 - Another story of complaining and jealousy. The story centers around Korah who is a Levite but not a priest. He complains about the role Aaron and Moses have, which God hears and views as sinful. This story is demonstrating again that the Israelites' complaining against the leaders is showing their distrust of God, because God established their leaders.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar7">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?67</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
  <title>March 8</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.17.NIV">Numbers 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.18.NIV">Numbers 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.10.31-32.NIV">Proverbs 10:31-32</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 17- After the complaining and rebellion of the people against their leadership, God performs this miracle to show He is behind Moses and Aaron, and will provide for the people. They can trust Him. The staff is a good reminder to us to have visual representations of God's faithfulness because we are prone to forget.</p>
        <p>Numbers 18 - After the narrative blocks, we are back into a section of teaching. The previous stories demonstrate how even if the people see God's faithfulness repeatedly, they're still prone to rebel, complain, and ultimately sin. They need a mediator between themselves and God. This teaching block gives some guidelines for the priests who will meditate on behalf of the people when they fall short.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 10:31-32 - These verses contain more parallelisms. Wisdom knows what is acceptable and right and is displayed in how someone speaks.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar8">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?68</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 9</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.19.NIV">Numbers 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.20.NIV">Numbers 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.35.17-21.NIV">Psalm 35:17-21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.1-3.NIV">Proverbs 11:1-3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.5.NIV">Luke 5</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 19- We read today the tragic story of Moses not being able to go into the Promised Land. This may seem harsh to us, but the reason is because of a lack of trust in the Lord. Moses' actions were an indication of his faith. Even the leaders missed opportunities to trust God. It is sobering to read about the very leaders who saw God part the Red Sea not trust Him for basic necessities.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 11:1-3 - The weight and scale were used in trade in the ancient world. People would modify them to cheat people in deals. The Lord desires for us to treat people fairly and honestly. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar9">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?69</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 10</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.21.NIV">Numbers 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.22.NIV">Numbers 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.35.22-28.NIV">Psalm 35:22-28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.4.NIV">Proverbs 11:4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.6.NIV">Luke 6</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 21-22 - Finally entering Moab, the journey that should've taken a week has taken decades. The king of Moab, Balak, summons a prophet for hire. He's not connected with Israel, but God uses him to show God is going to fulfill His promises. No person or empire will stop Him. The story of the donkey is meant to be hilarious, it's okay to read it with a smile on your face! God can even use a donkey when a "prophet" doesn't get it.</p>
        <p>Luke 6 - Jesus performs miracles that verify His identity. When He calls his disciples to the role of Apostles this means "Sent ones". They are being sent to bring the news of this King to the world.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar10">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?70</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 11</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.23.NIV">Numbers 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.24.NIV">Numbers 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.36.NIV">Psalm 36</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.5-6.NIV">Proverbs 11:5-6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.7.NIV">Luke 7</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 23 - 24 - Today's passage gives the prophecies of Balaam. Though he was hired to "curse" the Israelites, God won't let Him and instead promises something incredible. God promises a King who will come out of Israel. The promise is pointing to the ultimate King... Jesus.</p>
        <p>Luke 7 - Jesus is healing a Roman general's servant (radical for a Jewish person to be compassionate to the oppressive Romans!), and Jesus is even stronger than death raising a widow's son (1st century widow's only hope of survival was her children's care). These are people you wouldn't expect the Messiah to spend time with. This is Good News for everyone. In between these accounts, we see John in prison, wrestling with his expectations of the Messiah. Jesus reminds him the mission is bigger than being freed from Rome.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar11">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?71</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 12</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.25.NIV">Numbers 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.26.NIV">Numbers 26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.37.1-9.NIV">Psalm 37:1-9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.7.NIV">Proverbs 11:7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.8.NIV">Luke 8</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 25-26 - Today's story seems odd, but the people just heard how God was going to use them to influence the world in the last two chapters. Instead they are being influenced by the people around them to turn away from God.</p>
        <p>Psalm 37:1-9 - "Delight yourself in the LORD and He will give you the desires of your heart." An often misunderstood statement. The author is getting at the truth that when our hearts find purpose/joy in our relationship with God, then we see our desires aligning with His. </p>
        <p>Luke 8 - In this chapter, we get a picture of Jesus even having control of creation and the weather; to which the disciples utter a question reminiscent of Psalm 107:29-30. A true demonstration of who He is.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar12">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?72</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 13</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.27.NIV">Numbers 27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.28.NIV">Numbers 28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.37.10-17.NIV">Psalm 37:10-17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.8.NIV">Proverbs 11:8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.9.NIV">Luke 9</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 27 - Land was important to the promise of God to Israel. This provision for a man who doesn't have sons was radical in the ancient world because daughters never inherited anything. This shows God's heart of care for the overlooked and voiceless. </p>
        <p>Luke 9 - This is the turning point of Luke's Gospel. We read about Jesus sending out the Apostles to announce God's kingdom. Along with this announcement, the Apostles claim and see Jesus for who He truly is. Verse 51 is the turning point, where Jesus resolutely sets out for Jerusalem; this is Him marching toward Jerusalem non-stop, where the cross is waiting for Him. The rest of the story is the road trip to the cross.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar13">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?73</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 14</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.29.NIV">Numbers 29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.30.NIV">Numbers 30</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.9-11.NIV">Proverbs 11:9-11</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 29 - Today's reading offers a further explanation of offerings, you'll see a repeated phrase that the offering or aroma is pleasing to the Lord. It's not the smoke or dead animal itself that is pleasing; it's the person's faith that pleases God. </p>
        <p>Numbers 30 - This chapter highlights teaching on vows; it reveals how important it is to keep our word, because God keeps His vows and promises to us. We're like Him when we do the same. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar14">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?74</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 15</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.31.NIV">Numbers 31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.32.NIV">Numbers 32</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.12-13.NIV">Proverbs 11:12-13</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 31 - This chapter shows the retribution of the people who led Israel astray in chapter 25. This chapter emphasizes that God's people need to be set apart, the redemptive plan of the world is at stake.</p>
        <p>Numbers 32 - Here we see two tribes of Israel who find good grazing land for cattle outside of the Promised Land. The Lord allows this request to care for His people.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 11:12-13 - A good couple of verses that remind us to listen more than we speak. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar15">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?75</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
    <title>March 16</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/26z_KhwNdD8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.33.NIV">Numbers 33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.34.NIV">Numbers 34</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.37.18-24.NIV">Psalm 37:18-24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.14.NIV">Proverbs 11:14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.10.NIV">Luke 10</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 33 - Concluding the book, we read about Moses recounting the journey from Egypt to the wilderness travels. The hope is to see God's faithfulness; people are prone to forget, so remembering and seeing God's faithfulness is vital.</p>
        <p>Numbers 34 - We may be uncomfortable with the driving out of the Canaanites in the land. Remember the ancient mindset, each tribe has "god(s)" they worshipped; in battle, the victor's god was "superior". In this case, their gods would be seen as more powerful than the one true God. God didn't hate the Canaanites, but He didn't want Israel coerced into following their idols/gods (which is what will happen when we read the book of Judges). They never drove the Canaanites out, and they began to adopt their gods and customs in the future.</p>
        <p>Luke 10 - As Jesus is journeying to Jerusalem, He continues to announce God's Kingdom, and teaches here the famous story of the Good Samaritan. In the story, the road to Jericho was infamous for thieves and bandits. Also note that Samaritans were hated people by the Jewish audience, yet the Samaritan acts more like God than the Jewish priests in the story!</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar16">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?76</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 17</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.35.NIV">Numbers 35</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NUM.36.NIV">Numbers 36</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.37.25-29.NIV">Psalm 37:25-29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.15.NIV">Proverbs 11:15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.11.NIV">Luke 11</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Numbers 35-36 - The instructions given here were unprecedented for its day. The land can be given back to the original family every 50 years (The Year of Jubilee) even if a man never has a son (remember chapter 27). This was a beautiful way to remember that family forever. It also helped the people who sold their lands in hard times. The tragedy is in 2 Chronicles 36 Israel would choose to not celebrate the Year of Jubilee in the future.</p>
        <p>Luke 11 - This chapter shows, as Jesus journeys to the cross, that the resistance from the religious leaders is growing. This culminates with "The Woes" speech Jesus gives about the religious leaders. Jesus is stating they have made following God harder... They added rules that kept people from turning to God. </p>
         <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar17">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?77</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 18</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q5QEH9bH8AU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.1.NIV">Deuteronomy 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.2.NIV">Deuteronomy 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.37.30-34.NIV">Psalm 37:30-34</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.16-17.NIV">Proverbs 11:16-17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.12.NIV">Luke 12</a></li>
        </ul>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar18">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?78</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

 <item>
  <title>March 19</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.3.NIV">Deuteronomy 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.4.NIV">Deuteronomy 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.37.35-40.NIV">Psalm 37:35-40</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.18-19.NIV">Proverbs 11:18-19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.13.NIV">Luke 13</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 3 - This is another recounting of God's hand on the Israelites as they passed through the wilderness. This is all meant to recount God's faithfulness, so they can remember and trust Him moving forward. Trust is directly related to experience.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 11:18-19 - Wickedness and cheating may feel like they pay off, but in the long run wisdom and righteousness are what count. </p>
        <p>Luke 13 - Jesus is teaching more emphatically that the values of God's Kingdom are in direct conflict with many of humanity's selfish values. We are confronted with which we will choose. These commands may seem extreme, but this is a common Jewish teaching technique; teaching hyperbolically helps drive home the point.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar19">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?79</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 20</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.5.NIV">Deuteronomy 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.6.NIV">Deuteronomy 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.38.1-12.NIV">Psalm 38:1-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.20-21.NIV">Proverbs 11:20-21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.14.NIV">Luke 14</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 5-6 - Chapter 6 begins with what's often called "The Shema" (the word means Hear). The main idea is this: Hear Israel, God is one; love Him with everything you have and all that you are. It was prayed daily by the ancient Jewish people, and Jesus stated that it is the most important command in the New Testament. This chapter was core to who God is and His promises.</p>
        <p>Luke 14 - Jesus begins demonstrating the rift between the values of God's Kingdom and the values of the religious leaders. This leads to Jesus explaining what a follower of His needs to give up to follow Him.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar20">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?80</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 21</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.7.NIV">Deuteronomy 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.8.NIV">Deuteronomy 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.22.NIV">Proverbs 11:22</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 7 - God wants Israel to drive out the people who would violently and perversely lead them and others astray.</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 8 - This chapter serves as a reminder in Moses' speech of the faithfulness of God to the people even in their rebellion in the wilderness. Past faithfulness by God should provoke future trust in God.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 11:22 - A humorous verse reminding us that foolishness isn't remedied by outward beauty, only by wisdom. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar21">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?81</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 22</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.9.NIV">Deuteronomy 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.10.NIV">Deuteronomy 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.23.NIV">Proverbs 11:23</a></li>

        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 9 - The speech continues to show Israel has a heart issue, and they were not chosen because they were better than all the other nations. The golden calf story is a reminder of that heart issue, and a good reminder to us that God saved us not because of some inherent goodness in us, but because He is good.</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 10 - We see here "circumcise your hearts" and that sounds super odd. It was a picture for the Israelites that they need a heart change. The outward behavior is meaningless without a changed heart before God. The prophets (Jeremiah 4:4) later and the New Testament (Romans 2) will pick up on this theme and show the heart change had to come by the Spirit through Christ.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar22">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?82</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 23</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.11.NIV">Deuteronomy 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.12.NIV">Deuteronomy 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.38.13-22.NIV">Psalm 38:13-22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.24-26.NIV">Proverbs 11:24-26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.15.NIV">Luke 15</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 11-12 - A call is made here to love God. Notice all the relational terms Moses is using. In order to change the heart, our obedience must be linked with a sincere love for God rooted in what He has done for us.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 11:24-26 - A beautiful truth on generosity. Giving leads to blessing- not necessarily materialistic, but a deeper spiritual enrichment. </p>
        <p>Luke 15 -  Here we have the three "lost" parables. Notice the progression: 1% of the sheep are lost, 10% of the coins are lost, and 50% (or 100% if you also count the older brother) of the sons are lost. Powerful stories on the compassionate heart of God. Consider who was listening: sinners and the religious leaders. The story is for both groups. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar23">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?83</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 24</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.13.NIV">Deuteronomy 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.14.NIV">Deuteronomy 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.39.NIV">Psalm 39</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.27.NIV">Proverbs 11:27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.16.NIV">Luke 16</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 13 -  Moses and God knew there was such a draw for the Israelites (and us) toward idolatry, that prophets needed to be verifiable. If they were not sent from God, the people would listen and easily get led astray. This will happen later in the future in Jeremiah.</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 14 - The Israelite diet was to facilitate them being set apart for God from surrounding people. The chapter speaks of tithes, which means a tenth. The New Testament will repurpose this for believers in 2 Corinthians 8.</p>
        <p>Psalm 39 - A Psalm that causes us to remember the brevity of life, therefore our hope needs to be in the Lord.</p>
        <p>Luke 16 - Jesus' teaching is now getting into the eternal ramifications. Are you a part of the Kingdom of God or do you hold the values of humanity? It will shape eternity and how you live today.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar24">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?84</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 25</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.15.NIV">Deuteronomy 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.16.NIV">Deuteronomy 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.40.NIV">Psalm 40</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.28.NIV">Proverbs 11:28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.17.NIV">Luke 17</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 15 - This chapter highlights the Sabbatical year. It shows God cares for His creation (taking care of the land) and the poor (helping the people who were unfortunate). It's a picture of God's heart for humanity and creation. (Exodus 23 and Leviticus 25)</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 16 - This chapter goes over the three main Israelite holidays. These all have symbolic pictures designed to highlight what God had done for the people. This is similar to how images in our day remind us of historical events: like the food at Thanksgiving reminding us of the first Thanksgiving.</p>
        <p>Luke 17 - Notice that the only man to return and thank Jesus was a Samaritan. The Jewish people would not have expected the Samaritan to be the one to return; Samaritans were the outcasts of Jewish society.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar25">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?85</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 26</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.17.NIV">Deuteronomy 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.18.NIV">Deuteronomy 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.41.NIV">Psalm 41</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.11.29-31.NIV">Proverbs 11:29-31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.18.NIV">Luke 18</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 17 - Moses gives the rules for the king that Israel would have one day. These rules would all eventually be broken by Israel's kings. Jesus would be the first King to fulfill this command.</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 18 - Jewish people in the 1st century AD believed this encompassed a promise of a Final Prophet, and the Apostles saw this Final Prophet as Jesus. (Acts 3, Acts 7, & John 1:21).</p>
        <p>Luke 18 - We continue to see Jesus' heart for the poor, the hurting, and the outcasts. This all goes against the values of the religious leaders. Luke's account has Jesus paying special attention to poor and outcasts.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar26">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?86</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

<item>
  <title>March 27</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.19.NIV">Deuteronomy 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.20.NIV">Deuteronomy 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.42.NIV">Psalm 42</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.1.NIV">Proverbs 12:1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.19.NIV">Luke 19</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 19-20 - Moses provides instructions for how to deal with civil and criminal matters. This was revolutionary for the ancient world. Wrongdoers and enemy combatants were normally dehumanized, but God is demonstrating they are still created in His image.</p>
        <p>Psalm 42 - As the deer pants for water... This is a great metaphor for how our hearts need God. Without God our hearts are dead, we need a connection with Him for life.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:1 - Discipline and correction are important to growth; wisdom leads to this kind of lifestyle. </p>
        <p>Luke 19 - The story comes to a head as Jesus finally enters Jerusalem. During his "Triumphal Entry" He is praised as King, but inside the city of Jerusalem, Jesus will face the cross.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar27">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?87</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
  <title>March 28</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.21.NIV">Deuteronomy 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.22.NIV">Deuteronomy 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.2-3.NIV">Proverbs 12:2-3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 21 - These instructions are various ways for how to not desecrate the land. There was still a need for justice and care even to the foreign person. It culminates with a regulation to not leave anyone hanging on a tree overnight. Paul will link this to Jesus in Galatians 3:13. </p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 22 - These are various regulations about how to care for a neighbor's properties and how to avoid the deception, perversion, and manipulation linked with idol worship.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar28">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?88</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

    <item>
  <title>March 29</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.23.NIV">Deuteronomy 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.24.NIV">Deuteronomy 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.4.NIV">Proverbs 12:4</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 23 - This is who to exclude from worshipping, and may seem strange to you as you read. But these exclusions were to prevent worship of the One True God from looking like that of the polytheistic peoples around Israel.</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 24 - The regulations for divorce are examples of God protecting the woman from exploitation, which was unheard of in the ancient near east. Other various laws which protect people are included as well. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar29">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?89</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

    <item>
  <title>March 30</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.25.NIV">Deuteronomy 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.26.NIV">Deuteronomy 26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.43.NIV">Psalm 43</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.5-7.NIV">Proverbs 12:5-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.20.NIV">Luke 20</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 25-26 - The continuation for regulations centering around protection of specific groups of people like widows, businesses, etc. This leads to the next block of teaching about offerings that are given to remember that God is the one who provides.</p>
        <p>Psalm 43 - We control our hearts and feelings. We can command our hearts to worship God, even when we do not feel like it.</p>
        <p>Luke 20 - Here we see some of the final teachings of Jesus' life in Luke. The religious leaders are missing God's Kingdom and His heart for them. They're focused on the wrong idea of what the Promised King would look like. They wanted one who would overthrow Rome. Jesus challenges this notion with the tax argument, but wants to demonstrate the values of this upside down Kingdom through rebuking them.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar30">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?90</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>  

    <item>
  <title>March 31</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.27.NIV">Deuteronomy 27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.28.NIV">Deuteronomy 28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.44.1-16.NIV">Psalm 44:1-16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.8-9.NIV">Proverbs 12:8-9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.21.NIV">Luke 21</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 27- This chapter introduces the consequences for the Israelites if they do not keep the Covenant. God will keep His end of the Covenant, but if the people don't keep theirs, it leads to curses. Spoiler- the people don't keep the Covenant. God will have to make a new covenant not dependent on the behavior of the people. </p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:8-9 - These verses highlight that we don't need to put on a show. Convicting verses for us who fall into the comparison trap. </p>
        <p>Luke 21 - This is Jesus' last public teaching before His death. He's now showing where the religious leaders' values will lead them ultimately: to the destruction of the temple and Jerusalem. This comes to pass in 70 AD, when the Romans destroyed Jerusalem. Jesus also predicts His triumph and second coming where He will come in the clouds in glory and finally bring God's Kingdom. But before any of that can happen, He will have to first go to the cross and die, extending the Kingdom to the world.</p> 
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Mar31">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?91</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item> 

  </channel>
</rss>
