<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Daily Reading</title>
  <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
  <link>https://newheights.org</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

  <!-- <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/.NIV"></a></li> -->
  <!-- <iframe src="https://youtu.be/JqOqJlFF_eU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe> -->

  <item>
    <title>July 1</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.23.NIV">1 Chronicles 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.24.NIV">1 Chronicles 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.89.1-4.NIV">Psalm 89:1-4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.8.NIV">Proverbs 18:8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.14.NIV">Romans 14</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 23-24: These are not easy chapters to read. They seem "boring." But remember, David is preparing the nation to have a temple. With the coming construction of the temple, the worship will need to be organized. So in these chapters, he focuses on the Levites (chapter 23) and all the priests (chapter 24).</p>
        <p>Proverbs 18:8: This is a powerful verse about gossip. The truth of this verse is no different 3000 years after it was originally written. </p>
        <p>Romans 14: This chapter begins the practical teaching about how to view differences among Christians. It is such a stark contrast to the reading in Chronicles. The Old Testament had over 600 laws that were to be followed. Things were black and white - right or wrong. In the New Testament, without the civil and ceremonial laws, there is much more freedom, which means much more disagreement and different viewpoints. And chapters 14-15 help Christ-followers navigate those differences. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul1">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?181</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>July 2</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.25.NIV">1 Chronicles 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.26.NIV">1 Chronicles 26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.89.5-18.NIV">Psalm 89:5-18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.9-10.NIV">Proverbs 18:9-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.15.NIV">Romans 15</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 25-26: These are two more chapters with lots of names and not a lot of action. But the writer is wanting us to be aware of how serious David is in setting up the temple to be the center place of worship for God's people. Chapter 25 shows how important music is in the worship of God. As you read, may it remind you of what a blessing it is to be part of God's family after the cross where we are God's temple - not a building we must travel to so that we can connect with God.</p>
        <p>Romans 15: This is one of Paul's two longest letters (this and 1 Corinthians). And after a book full of heavy doctrine about salvation and sanctification, Paul begins to get a bit personal at the end of the letter (starting in verse 14). The glimpses of Paul's personal life and feelings allow us to see behind the theologian, missionary, and teacher. He will continue the personal part of his letter in the final chapter.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul2">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?182</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 3</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.27.NIV">1 Chronicles 27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.28.NIV">1 Chronicles 28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.89.19-24.NIV">Psalm 89:19-24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.11-12.NIV">Proverbs 18:11-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.16.NIV">Romans 16</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 27: It is interesting that so many chapters were spent on instructions surrounding the worship of God at the temple, and only one chapter (27) gives instructions about the military leaders and tribal leaders. The emphasis of David is clear, even though it isn't the most interesting reading for us.</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 28: David now will give his heart behind all the details surrounding the worship of God. In this chapter he gives a charge to the people and to his son. It reveals David's heart and desire behind the final acts of his life.</p>
        <p>Psalm 89: How appropriate that these verses from Psalm 89 are about God's covenant with David. It ties very well together with 1 Chronicles 28.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul3">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?183</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 4</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.29.NIV">1 Chronicles 29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.13.NIV">Proverbs 18:13</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 29: David puts his "money where his mouth is" and where his prayers are. He does more than pray and give instructions - he gives to the project to help it succeed. Verses 14-16 provide a great theology of possessions and giving.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 18:13: This is a great verse that serves as a reminder to be slow to speak and quick to listen. We have a tendency to answer quickly, before we've heard what is truly said.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul4">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?184</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 5</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.1.NIV">2 Chronicles 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.2.NIV">2 Chronicles 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.14-15.NIV">Proverbs 18:14-15</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 1-2: The books of Kings and the books of Chronicles retell some of the same stories and cover the same period of history, but the books of Chronicles focus primarily on David, Solomon, and then the southern kings. The first nine chapters of 2 Chronicles are about Solomon's life and reign. The rest of the book will focus on the southern kings during the time of the Divided Kingdom. On the other hand, the last 11 chapters of 1 Kings and the entire book of 2 Kings tells stories of both the northern and the southern Kingdoms. Occasionally, as you read Chronicles, you will learn what is happening in the northern tribes, but it is typically only mentioned when it connects with what is happening in the south.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul5">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?185</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 6</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/yiHf8klCCc4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.3.NIV">2 Chronicles 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.4.NIV">2 Chronicles 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.89.25-37.NIV">Psalm 89:25-37</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.16-18.NIV">Proverbs 18:16-18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.1.NIV">1 Corinthians 1</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 3-4: The emphasis on the temple continues as the temple is built and finished. It is helpful to remember that the temple, once built, is the only location where someone can meet with God. Imagine COVID-19 happening during OT days when you were required to go to the temple to meet with God. Thankfully, today we don't have to show up at a building to worship God or to seek forgiveness for sins. As you read, thank the Lord that we live after the cross - where there is no separation between us and God because of Jesus.</p>
        <p>1 Corinthians: Watch the video from The Bible Project. It will help you understand what is coming as you read 1 Corinthians in the month of July.</p>
        
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul6">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?186</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 7</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.5.NIV">2 Chronicles 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.6.NIV">2 Chronicles 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.89.38-52.NIV">Psalm 89:38-52</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.19.NIV">Proverbs 18:19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.2.NIV">1 Corinthians 2</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 5-6: These chapters continue with the emphasis on the temple with the emphasis on the most holy item (the ark of the covenant) being put in the most holy place (the temple). Solomon's prayer of dedication focuses on his longing for God to hear the prayers of His people. Notice how many times he repeats the request in chapter 6.</p>
        <p>1 Corinthians 2: The first four chapters of the book center on divisions in the church. And this chapter reminds people of the unity we have because of the Gospel. We are united by the Spirit because of the Good News of Jesus.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul7">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?187</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 8</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.7.NIV">2 Chronicles 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.8.NIV">2 Chronicles 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.90.NIV">Psalm 90</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.20-21.NIV">Proverbs 18:20-21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.3.NIV">1 Corinthians 3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 7: God's answer to Solomon's prayer comes in two parts. First, fire came from heaven (vv. 1-3). Then God gives a direct response to Solomon's prayer (vv. 11-22). God tells Solomon that prayers from the temple aren't enough for his blessing. He requires obedience from His people. </p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 8: We read much about David's wars and conquests. But Solomon's great accomplishment was not war. It was the temple. And this chapter begins the conclusion of Solomon's reign. By the end of chapter 9, Solomon will be dead.</p>
                
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul8">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?188</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 9</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.9.NIV">2 Chronicles 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.10.NIV">2 Chronicles 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.91.NIV">Psalm 91</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.22.NIV">Proverbs 18:22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.4.NIV">1 Corinthians 4</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 9-10: Both chapters end on a very sad note. At the end of chapter 9, Solomon dies. At the end of chapter 10, the United Kingdom also dies, and we now enter the time of the Divided Kingdom. As mentioned previously, Chronicles will focus on the Southern Kingdom, while the books of Kings dealt with both the Northern and Southern Kingdoms.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 18:22: This verse harkens back to Genesis 2:18 when we are told that it is not good for the man to be alone.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul9">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?189</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 10</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.11.NIV">2 Chronicles 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.12.NIV">2 Chronicles 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.92.NIV">Psalm 92</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.23-24.NIV">Proverbs 18:23-24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.5.NIV">1 Corinthians 5</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 11-12: These two chapters are about the reign of Rehoboam, the son of Solomon. There are two things to notice at the end of chapter 12 that you will read regularly in this book. First, we are typically given a summary of whether a king was good or evil. We read that summary in 12:14 ("he did evil, for he did not set his heart to seek the Lord."). Second, we are given an indication that the writer used sources (v. 15). Theologically, that isn't a problem for inerrancy and inspiration. God can lead a writer to include material from another source. It doesn't change its accuracy or its inspiration.</p>
        <p>1 Corinthians 5: This is one of the strangest passages in the Bible. It seems a man in good standing in the church was sexually involved with his step-mom. Commentators believe it is his step-mom because it labels the woman as his father's wife rather than his mother. This passage, as strange as it is, helps give churches today a path and plan for handling Christians who are making terrible, sinful choices.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul10">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?190</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 11</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.13.NIV">2 Chronicles 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.14.NIV">2 Chronicles 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.1-3.NIV">Proverbs 19:1-3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 13: If you read this chapter, you would assume that Abijah was one of the good kings of Judah. But if you read 1 Kings 15:1-8, it is clear he was not a good king. Many times, the Chronicler will tell you if a king was good or evil, but this time he does not. The books of Chronicles tend to view the kings of Judah (Southern Kingdom) more positively than the writer of the books of Kings does. The stories don't disagree, but the author of 1 Kings clearly labeled him as not following God wholeheartedly.</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 14: On the other hand, Asa was clearly labeled as a good king (v. 2) Asa's story lasts for three chapters. As a good king, the Chronicler wants to tell us more about him than he typically would tell us of the evil kings.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul11">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?191</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 12</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.15.NIV">2 Chronicles 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.16.NIV">2 Chronicles 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.4-5.NIV">Proverbs 19:4-5</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 15-16: These are two chapters about the reign of King Asa (which began in chapter 14). We already know that he was a good king (14:2), and we are told that again in 15:17. But chapter 16 gives the other side, and Asa's life and reign doesn't end well. But I am so encouraged by the grace and mercy of God seen in God's summary of his life (15:17) knowing that he didn't end well. 2 Chronicles 16:9 is a great verse reminding us that God is looking for those whose hearts are devoted to Him. May that encourage us to pursue Him fully. It is a verse I had my (David's) daughters memorize when they were young.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul12">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?192</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 13</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.17.NIV">2 Chronicles 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.18.NIV">2 Chronicles 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.93.NIV">Psalm 93</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.6-7.NIV">Proverbs 19:6-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.6.NIV">1 Corinthians 6</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 17-18: We have four chapters in Chronicles about Jehoshaphat. He was one of the good kings of Judah (17:3-4). Chapter 18 begins by telling us that he made a marriage alliance with Ahab (the wicked king of the Northern Kingdom). Why would Jehoshaphat do that? Alliances between countries were most commonly accomplished through marriage. If your daughter is the queen of a neighboring country, you would be less likely to attack that country. It was a common strategy to keep peace.</p>
        <p>1 Corinthians 6: This is another short chapter that is incredibly practical for modern believers. In the first half, Paul argues why Christians should not sue each other. In the second half of the chapter, he urges Christians to be sexually moral. It ends with two of the best known verses from the book of 1 Corinthians.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul13">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?193</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 14</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.19.NIV">2 Chronicles 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.20.NIV">2 Chronicles 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.94.1-11.NIV">Psalm 94:1-11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.8-9.NIV">Proverbs 19:8-9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.7.NIV">1 Corinthians 7</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 20: There is an amazing story of the Moabites and Ammonites making war with Jehoshaphat, and an interesting comparison can be made with how Asa responded. Notice Jehoshaphat's response (v. 3): he prayed and proclaimed a fast for the nation. Compare that to what Asa did in 16:2. Asa made a treaty with an enemy nation to defend him. He didn't go to God. He went to his neighbor for help. Also notice the results for Jehoshaphat (20:29-30) and Asa (16:7-9). That is an amazing contrast and comparison between two kings' responses when in trouble. The summary for Jehoshaphat is found in 20:31-32. "He did what was right in the eyes of the Lord." Notice in v. 32, he didn't do it fully, but God is merciful and gracious in His summary of Jehoshaphat. Finally, notice, he did not end well (vv. 34-37).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul14">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?194</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 15</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.21.NIV">2 Chronicles 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.22.NIV">2 Chronicles 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.94.12-23.NIV">Psalm 94:12-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.10-12.NIV">Proverbs 19:10-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.8.NIV">1 Corinthians 8</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 21: The harshness with which the Chronicler speaks of Jehoram is surprising. It starts (v. 4) with us being told that he killed all his brothers to eliminate any threats to his throne (since the throne stayed in the family line). His summary is given in verses 5-6. He was compared to the kings of the Northern tribes who were all wicked kings. And he is specifically compared to the wicked king Ahab. Verse 7 reminds us of God's faithfulness even in sin. Verse 20 provides a shocking ending, as we discover no one was bothered that he died, and he was buried without honor.</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 22: We have two more rulers - a king (Ahaziah) and a queen (Athaliah). Both are evil. Ahaziah's summary is found in verses 2-4. Athaliah is not given a similar summary, but the story clearly shows her wickedness.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul15">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?195</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 16</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.23.NIV">2 Chronicles 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.24.NIV">2 Chronicles 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.95.NIV">Psalm 95</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.13-14.NIV">Proverbs 19:13-14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.9.NIV">1 Corinthians 9</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 23-24: These two chapters focus on a good king, Joash. His summary is found in 24:1-2. Sadly, his reign did not end well either (vv. 17-20).</p>
        <p>Psalm 95: This is a popular Psalm that begins as a great praise Psalm, but it is one of the few Psalms that ends with a negative statement. The last four verses are a reminder of the rebellious generation who died in the wilderness. It is a Psalm with two very distinctive tones: joyful praise of God (vv. 1-7) and a dire warning against rebellion (vv. 8-11).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul16">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?196</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 17</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.25.NIV">2 Chronicles 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.26.NIV">2 Chronicles 26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.96.NIV">Psalm 96</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.15-16.NIV">Proverbs 19:15-16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.10.NIV">1 Corinthians 10</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 25: Amaziah was the king of Judah for 29 years and his summary is found in verse 2: "He did what was right in the eyes of the LORD, but not wholeheartedly." </p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 26: Uzziah was the next king of Judah and reigned for 52 years. His positive summary is found in verses 4-5. A foreshadowing hint is given in verse 5 where it says: "As long as he sought the LORD, God gave him success." That sounds like maybe he wouldn't always follow the Lord. And in verse 16, we read this: "But after Uzziah became powerful, his pride led to his downfall."</p>
        <p>Psalm 96: This is a great Psalm of praise that is worth reading and using as a personal prayer/praise to God. It is a great reminder of how great our God is.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul17">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?197</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 18</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.27.NIV">2 Chronicles 27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.28.NIV">2 Chronicles 28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.17.NIV">Proverbs 19:17</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 27: Jotham was one of the good kinds of Israel, although he didn't lead the people away from false worship (27:2). We are not only told he was a king who did what was right, but we are also told he grew powerful because he was faithful to God (v. 6).</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 28: In contrast, we have Ahaz's story. He was an evil kind and walked in the ways of the Northern kings (vv. 1-2). Verse 22-23 tell us how Ahaz responded when trouble came - he abandoned God and began to worship other gods. This led to his downfall and the downfall of the nation. What a sad story.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 19:17: This verse provides a great reason to be generous to needy people.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul18">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?198</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 19</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.29.NIV">2 Chronicles 29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.30.NIV">2 Chronicles 30</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.18-19.NIV">Proverbs 19:18-19</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 29: This begins four chapters on the story of Hezekiah - one of the great kings of Israel. The account in 2 Kings give us a strong commentary on his life: "Hezekiah trusted in the Lord, the God of Israel. There was no one like him among all the kings of Judah, either before him or after him. He held fast to the Lord and did not cease to follow him." (2 Kings 18:5-6)</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 30: At the end of two chapters of reform, verse 26 tells us how significant Hezekiah's reforms were: "There was great joy in Jerusalem, for since the days of Solomon son of David king of Israel there had been nothing like this in Jerusalem." </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul19">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?199</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 20</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.31.NIV">2 Chronicles 31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.32.NIV">2 Chronicles 32</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.97.NIV">Psalm 97</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.20-21.NIV">Proverbs 19:20-21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.11.NIV">1 Corinthians 11</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 31: By the end of chapter 31, the commentary on Hezekiah is amazing: "This is what Hezekiah did throughout Judah, doing what was good and right and faithful before the Lord his God. In everything that he undertook in the service of God's temple and in obedience to the law and the commands, he sought his God and worked wholeheartedly. And so he prospered." The final chapter of his story (chapter 32) doesn't end as well.</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 32: Verse 30 talks about the work Hezekiah did to bring water into the city. To this day, thousands of years later, you can walk through the very tunnel that Hezekiah built to bring water into the city of Jerusalem. It is an engineering marvel and one of the most amazing things to see in Jerusalem.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul20">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?200</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 21</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.33.NIV">2 Chronicles 33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.34.NIV">2 Chronicles 34</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.98.NIV">Psalm 98</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.22-23.NIV">Proverbs 19:22-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.12.NIV">1 Corinthians 12</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 33 - Sadly, Hezekiah's son and grandson were evil kings (vv. 1-6 & vv. 32-33). The ultimate battle in the Old Testament is a battle for monotheism. All the other nations worshipped multiple gods, and whenever Israel did what was wrong, it wasn't usually that they stopped worshipping God. They just added other gods to their worship practices.</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 34 - Thankfully, the next king is one of the best kings Israel had ever known (vv. 1-2). It is hard to imagine, but God's law had been so disregarded by the people that Josiah was unaware of it. And when he heard it, he repented and began to bring reforms to the nation again (v. 19).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul21">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?201</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 22</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.35.NIV">2 Chronicles 35</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CH.36.NIV">2 Chronicles 36</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.99.NIV">Psalm 99</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.24-25.NIV">Proverbs 19:24-25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.13.NIV">1 Corinthians 13</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 35: Verse 7 gives an idea of the amount of animals that would be sacrificed on a typical Passover. Josiah supplied animals for the first Passover after the reforms he brought. Verse 25 helps us understand how great Josiah's reign was as we are told Jeremiah wrote about Josiah.</p>
        <p>2 Chronicles 36: This chapter tells about the last four kings of the south - all of them are evil kings. The chapter also tells of the fall of Jerusalem. And it lists four reasons for the fall of the nation: v. 13 (rebellion against King Nebuchadnezzar), v. 14 (the people were unfaithful to the Lord), v. 16 (the people mocked God's prophets), and v. 21 (the people didn't give the land its Sabbath rest - one year of every seven). They had been in the land 490 years. So they missed 70 years of Sabbath rests for the land (see Leviticus 25:40-45).</p>
        
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul22">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?202</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 23</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
         <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/MkETkRv9tG8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.1.NIV">Ezra 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.2.NIV">Ezra 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.100.NIV">Psalm 100</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.26.NIV">Proverbs 19:26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.14.NIV">1 Corinthians 14</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ezra 1: I encourage you to watch the video summarizing Ezra and Nehemiah. It will help you understand what you will be reading over the next 12 days or so. These books are written after the exile to Babylon. They are rebuilding the Temple, the walls, and the people of Jerusalem.</p>
        <p>Ezra 2: Reading names can be difficult. I recommend using biblegateway.com or the youversion app and letting someone read the names to you.</p>
        <p>Psalm 100: One of my (David's) favorite Psalms. It is a Psalm of praise and filled with great commands for worshipping God.</p>
        
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul23">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?203</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 24</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.3.NIV">Ezra 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.4.NIV">Ezra 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.101.NIV">Psalm 101</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.19.27-29.NIV">Proverbs 19:27-29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.15.NIV">1 Corinthians 15</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ezra 3: This is the second temple. The first temple was built by Solomon and destroyed by the Babylonians. This second temple will be the one that Jesus will come to. It will be destroyed in 70AD and not rebuilt. </p>
        <p>1 Corinthians 15: This is Paul's thesis on the essentialness of the resurrection. He summarizes the gospel in verses 3-4. And for the rest of the chapter he reminds us of how important the resurrection is for us. And it ends with one of my favorite New Testament verses (v. 58).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul24">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?204</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 25</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.5.NIV">Ezra 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.6.NIV">Ezra 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.1.NIV">Proverbs 20:1</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ezra 5: Two of the four post-exilic prophets are mentioned here (Haggai and Zechariah). The building of the Temple was honoring to the Lord, but that didn't mean they refused governmental authority and help. Following God and appealing to the government aren't necessarily in opposition.</p>
        <p>Ezra 6: At the end of the chapter, the people celebrate the Passover for the first time in 70 years. How sweet that celebration must have been. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul25">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?205</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 26</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.7.NIV">Ezra 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.8.NIV">Ezra 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.2-3.NIV">Proverbs 20:2-3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ezra 7-8: Notice six times in these two chapters that the hand of God was with them. Three times in each chapter. If using a physical Bible, underline those verses. It will help remind you that ultimate success comes from God, no matter the opponents.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 20:3: A fool is quick to quarrel. Godly people are peacemakers. Fools love to argue. Be a wise peacemaker, not a foolish quarreler.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul26">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?206</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 27</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.9.NIV">Ezra 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EZR.10.NIV">Ezra 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.102.1-11.NIV">Psalm 102:1-11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.4-6.NIV">Proverbs 20:4-6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CO.16.NIV">1 Corinthians 16</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ezra 9-10: This can be a troubling passage. We know God hates divorce (Malachi 2:16), but seems to condone the decision that led to a massive divorce event. It is important to understand that the nationalities listed in 9:1-2 are the people who were supposed to be driven out from the Promised Land. There are two things to notice. First, the typical Hebrew word for divorce is not used. It may indicate they were not legitimate marriages, but cohabitations (so the dissolution of the relationship is appropriate). Second, even if they were legitimate marriages, the corruption the false worship brought to the people required an extreme response. Regardless, this is a difficult passage to understand and see how it fits with God's instructions on divorce. The Bible is difficult to understand, which is why it requires a lifetime of study.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul27">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?207</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 28</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/3lfPK2vfC54" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.1.NIV">Nehemiah 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.2.NIV">Nehemiah 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.102.12-22.NIV">Psalm 102:12-22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.7.NIV">Proverbs 20:7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CO.1.NIV">2 Corinthians 1</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Nehemiah 1-2: Besides the post-exilic prophets (Zephaniah, Haggai, Zechariah, Malachi), there are three main characters when the people returned from Babylon, and each played a specific role. Zerubbabel rebuilt the Temple, Nehemiah rebuilt the walls, and Ezra rebuilt the people. The book of Nehemiah is often used as a study of leadership. As you read, watch how Nehemiah led and how he served under someone who wasn't a follower of God. There is much to learn from this book.</p>
        <p>2 Corinthians 1: Be sure to watch the video on 2 Corinthians. It will help you understand the context, content, and flow of the book.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul28">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?208</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 29</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.3.NIV">Nehemiah 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.4.NIV">Nehemiah 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.102.23-28.NIV">Psalm 102:23-28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.8-10.NIV">Proverbs 20:8-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CO.2.NIV">2 Corinthians 2</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Nehemiah 3-4: The next four chapters is the story of the rebuilding of the wall of the city of Jerusalem. My (David's) favorite verse in the book of Nehemiah is 4:9. The people were up against a wall - literally and figuratively. They were under threat from Sanballat. So should they trust God or defend themselves? And verse 9 answers it for us. They do both. There are so many applications for our daily lives. Making wise decisions doesn't mean we don't trust God, and trusting God doesn't mean we don't make wise decisions. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul29">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?209</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 30</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.5.NIV">Nehemiah 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.6.NIV">Nehemiah 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.103.1-4.NIV">Psalm 103:1-4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.11.NIV">Proverbs 20:11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CO.3.NIV">2 Corinthians 3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 103: This is one of the most quoted Psalms. It is a great Psalm to read or quote when life is hard and we need to be reminded of God's goodness. </p>
        <p>2 Corinthians 3: This chapter ends with Paul applying the story of Moses and the veil to us. In Exodus 32-34, Moses would have to put on a veil after meeting with God because his face shone so brightly. The chapter ends suggesting that as we grow in our faith, we reflect the glory of God more and more. We look more like Jesus.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul30">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?210</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>July 31</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.7.NIV">Nehemiah 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/NEH.8.NIV">Nehemiah 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.103.15-22.NIV">Psalm 103:15-22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.20.12.NIV">Proverbs 20:12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2CO.4.NIV">2 Corinthians 4</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Nehemiah 7: It can be difficult to read a chapter full of names. We suggest using the audio feature on the YouVersion app to let it be read to you. And although it can be hard to follow, it is a reminder these are real people from history. </p>
        <p>2 Corinthians 4: This chapter gives us a great perspective of life here and now and the role we play (jars of clay - vv. 7-12). It also helps us understand suffering and why Christ-followers are able to suffer well (vv. 14-18). </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jul31">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?211</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  
  </channel>
</rss>