<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Daily Reading</title>
  <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
  <link>https://newheights.org</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

  <item>
    <title>April 1</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.29.NIV">Deuteronomy 29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.30.NIV">Deuteronomy 30</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.44.17-26.NIV">Psalm 44:17-26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.10.NIV">Proverbs 12:10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.22.NIV">Luke 22</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 29-30: We are getting to the end of the book. The people are getting ready to enter the Promised Land and Moses reminds them of God's covenant with them. They are about to receive the Land promised to Abraham, but Moses wants to be sure they get to stay there. So he reminds them to believe and follow God! How appropriate to read on April Fool's Day. The opposite of foolishness is to embrace God and His ways.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:10: If PETA were run by Christians, this ought to be their theme verse.</p>
        <p>Luke 22: The only one who never sinned endured such agony for us. As you read, be thankful.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr1">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?90</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 2</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.31.NIV">Deuteronomy 31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.32.NIV">Deuteronomy 32</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.45.NIV">Psalm 45</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.11.NIV">Proverbs 12:11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.23.NIV">Luke 23</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 32: The end of this chapter contains one of my (David's) favorite OT phrases: "Take to heart all the words I have solemnly declared to you this day... They are not just idle words for you - they are your life."</p>
        <p>Psalm 45: The beginning of verse 1 is a great phrase I often think of before we sing songs at church. "My heart is stirred by a noble theme as I recite (sing) my verses for the king." It was written about Israel's king, but I think of it when I praise the King of kings.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:11 - Proverbs is still incredibly practical and applicable millennia after it was written.</p>
        <p>Luke 23: It is easy to read this story that we are so familiar with and not see its importance. Read carefully and consider what Jesus did for you.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr2">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?91</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 3</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.33.NIV">Deuteronomy 33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/DEU.34.NIV">Deuteronomy 34</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.46.NIV">Psalm 46</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.12-14.NIV">Proverbs 12:12-14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/LUK.24.NIV">Luke 24</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Deuteronomy 34: Reading this chapter, it is no surprise that Moses is the most beloved of Israel's biblical leaders.</p>
        <p>Psalm 46: This is a great Psalm to return to when life is difficult and you are surrounded by trials. It contains one of the most popular verses in the Bible.</p>
        <p>Luke 24: The third Gospel ends with more details of Jesus post-resurrection than Matthew or Mark.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr3">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?92</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 4</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/JqOqJlFF_eU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.1.NIV">Joshua 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.2.NIV">Joshua 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.15-17.NIV">Proverbs 12:15-17</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 1: This chapter contains a repeated command and an amazing promise. The repeated command: "Be strong and courageous" is repeated a few times in this chapter. The amazing promise is in verse 5, "As I was with Moses, so I will be with you." When you consider how God worked in and through Moses, it is an amazing promise that would result in being strong and courageous.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:16 - There are many statements comparing the differences between the wise man and foolish man. This verse makes complete sense, but is so difficult to live it out.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr4">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?93</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 5</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.3.NIV">Joshua 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.4.NIV">Joshua 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.18.NIV">Proverbs 12:18</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 3: Verse 7 reiterates the promises of being with Joshua as He was with Moses. And it gives the natural result of that: the people will view Joshua differently. The Lord accomplished this through the parting of the Jordan River, similar to the parting of the Red Sea for Moses.</p>
        <p>Joshua 4: Verse 14 is the other side of the promise God gave Joshua that He would be with Joshua as He was with Moses. Now we begin to see the result of that. The Lord was with Joshua (as He was with Moses), and now the people viewed Joshua in the same way they viewed Moses.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:18 - You are reading only one verse, but don't move past it too quickly. We all know these words are true. Ask God to help you live out the second part of the verse, not the first.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr5">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?94</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 6</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/G-2e9mMf7E8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.5.NIV">Joshua 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.6.NIV">Joshua 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.47.NIV">Psalm 47</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.19-20.NIV">Proverbs 12:19-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.1.NIV">John 1</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 6: In verse 27, we see the theme repeated of the Lord being with Joshua along with the people having a high regard for Joshua. Also notice verse 26, in which Joshua issues a prophecy or curse concerning Jericho. It is a statement symbolizing the significance of the judgment on the Canaanites. See 1 Kings 16:34 when the prophecy will be fulfilled.</p>
        <p>John 1: It would be worth watching the video before you read the first half of the book of John. It helps understand the outline, purpose, and flow of the book. Chapter 1 begins differently than any other Gospel. It is a theological statement and a clear proclamation of the Divinity of Jesus. He truly is God.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr6">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?95</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 7</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.7.NIV">Joshua 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.8.NIV">Joshua 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.48.NIV">Psalm 48</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.21-23.NIV">Proverbs 12:21-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.2.NIV">John 2</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 7: This story is the only loss the Israel army has as they conquer the land. And there is a reason they lost this battle.</p>
        <p>Joshua 8: This chapter begins with the family command to Joshua, "Do not be afraid; do not be discouraged." The army attacks Ai again, and this time the results are far different.</p>
        <p>John 2: This chapter gives great insight into the heart of Jesus. First, he does a miracle because his mom wants him to (v. 4 indicates it wasn't time yet to reveal Himself). It also shows his love for God's Temple and his anger at those who misused it. It ends with a stark reminder of the depravity of mankind.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr7">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?96</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 8</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.9.NIV">Joshua 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.10.NIV">Joshua 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.49.1-11.NIV">Psalm 49:1-11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.24.NIV">Proverbs 12:24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.3.NIV">John 3</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 10: There are two verses that I (David) have underlined in my Bible from this chapter that amaze me. Verse 14 speaks of the power of prayer that amazed even the writer of the book of Joshua. Verse 42 is amazing about God fighting for Israel.</p>
        <p>Psalm 49: This is a Psalm all about who you trust, and it ends with the challenge of those who trust in money (vv. 16-20).</p>
        <p>John 3: This chapter contains the best known verse in the world. The chapter ends with a clear statement of the exclusivity of Jesus.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr8">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?97</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 9</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.11.NIV">Joshua 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.12.NIV">Joshua 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.49.12-20.NIV">Psalm 49:12-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.25.NIV">Proverbs 12:25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.4.NIV">John 4</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 11: These are now the battles for the northern part of the country. Remember, this is the land God promised His people and there is a constant emphasis on their obedience (vv. 9,12,14,20,23). Verses 19-20 also give us a theological viewpoint of what was happening.</p>
        <p>Joshua 12: The kings defeated by Moses and Joshua are listed, and this completes the major battles to take over the Promised Land.</p>
        <p>Psalm 49: The first half of the Psalm was about the common reality that we all die. This second half of the Psalm is about our contrasting destinies (we go to God, not destruction and judgment).</p>
        <p>Proverbs 12:25 - What a great reminder of the power of our words.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr9">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?98</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 10</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.13.NIV">Joshua 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.14.NIV">Joshua 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.50.1-15.NIV">Psalm 50:1-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.26.NIV">Proverbs 12:26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.5.NIV">John 5</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 13: This now begins the second half of the book, and this chapter begins much like chapter 1, with a comment about the status of the leader (chapter 1 was the death of Moses; chapter 13 is about the age of Joshua).</p>
        <p>Joshua 14: The second half of the book is concerned with dividing up the land between the tribes. It may be best to find a map of the nation with the tribal divisions shown. It may make it easier to follow along and be interested (Google "Tribal Division of Israel" and you will find a helpful map).</p>
        <p>Psalm 50: Here is an outline that may help you follow along:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>vv. 1-6 - God summons the earth to assemble before Him</li>
          <li>vv. 7-15 - God speaks to His people: Worship Him from the heart</li>
        </ul>
        <p>John 5: Verse 18 shows that being the "Son of God" is a statement of equality with God. Theologically, this is an important verse about the Deity of Christ.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr10">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?99</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 11</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.15.NIV">Joshua 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.16.NIV">Joshua 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.12.27-28.NIV">Proverbs 12:27-28</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 15: When verse 8 mentions that Jerusalem will be given to the tribe of Judah, they don't yet know that Jerusalem will be the city God chooses as His dwelling place, and will become the most important city in the world. Yet, we know from Genesis that from the tribe of Judah will come one who will rule God's people. So it shouldn't surprise us that Jerusalem (the city God will choose) will be given to the tribe of Judah. It also should not surprise us that an entire chapter is devoted to the chosen tribe of Judah (from whom Jesus will be born). Also notice the last verse of the chapter (a warning Moses had repeatedly given).</p>
        <p>Joshua 16: This much shorter chapter is devoted to the land given to the two sons of Joseph (the tribes of Ephraim and Manasseh). Jacob had 12 sons (the 12 tribes of Israel), but when it comes to the distribution of land, the priestly tribe of Levi is not given any land of their own, therefore, Joseph's two sons are each declared independent tribes for the purpose of land distribution. Notice the last verse of this chapter ends the same way chapter 15 did.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr11">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?100</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 12</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.17.NIV">Joshua 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.18.NIV">Joshua 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.1.NIV">Proverbs 13:1</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 17: Notice verses 12-13 continue the pattern of not driving the Canaanites out of the land. This will cause perpetual problems for the Israelites.</p>
        <p>Joshua 18: The tribe of Benjamin's territory is listed at the end of this chapter and it also contains the city of Jerusalem (that had been given to the tribe of Judah). Jerusalem shares the border with the tribes of Judah and Benjamin.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 13:1 - This is a verse every father loves while their sons are not as quick to appreciate it. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr12">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?101</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 13</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.19.NIV">Joshua 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.20.NIV">Joshua 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.50.16-23.NIV">Psalm 50:16-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.2-3.NIV">Proverbs 13:2-3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.6.NIV">John 6</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 19-20: The land is finally divided and cities of refuge are established.</p>
        <p>Psalm 50: We began this Psalm Friday. Here is a reminder of an outline that may help you follow along:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>vv. 16-22 - God speaks to the "wicked": He rebukes them</li>
          <li>vv. 23 - God sums it up: Worship Him with the heart</li>
        </ul>
        <p>John 6:60, 66 - Jesus loses some popularity when His teaching becomes difficult. It is interesting that it is still true today. Jesus is popular, as long as you only emphasize some (but not all) of His teachings. This chapter begins the first of 7 "I AM" statements in the book of John. Three times in this chapter Jesus will call himself the "bread of life." </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr13">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?102</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 14</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.21.NIV">Joshua 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.22.NIV">Joshua 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.51.NIV">Psalm 51</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.4.NIV">Proverbs 13:4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.7.NIV">John 7</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 21: Cities are given to the Levites. It is hard to get excited reading a list of cities, but the most important verse is the last verse of the chapter. The Lord had fulfilled every promise He had made.</p>
        <p>Joshua 22: The tribes who had requested to settle east of the Jordan River are allowed to go back to their homes after helping conquer the land. They are concerned that the river will be a significant border and divide them from the rest of the nation.</p>
        <p>Psalm 51: This is the best known Psalm of repentance in the Bible and models for us how to repent. Verse 11 is not a fear of losing his salvation, but a fear of losing his kingship. The Holy Spirit did not come and reside in every believer in the Old Testament. That is a blessing for New Testament believers. The Holy Spirit would come on certain people in the Old Testament for specific purposes (judges, kings, prophets, etc). David's prayer was that a consequence of his sin would not be to lose his role as king.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr14">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?103</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 15</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.23.NIV">Joshua 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JOS.24.NIV">Joshua 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.52.NIV">Psalm 52</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.5-6.NIV">Proverbs 13:5-6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.8.NIV">John 8</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Joshua 23-24: The land has been conquered. Joshua is about to die. And so he reminds them of the covenant that God had made with them. Joshua 24:31 gives us a hint that after this generation dies (who saw God do so much for the people), the people's willingness to keep God's covenant will begin to change. </p>
        <p>John 8: This chapter is filled with well-known statements of Jesus including His statement of being the "light of the world." Jesus makes 7 "I am" statements in John's Gospel. The first was in chapter 6 ("I am the bread of life"). Twice, He will say He is the light of the world (8:12; 9:5).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr15">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?104</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 16</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/kOYy8iCfIJ4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.1.NIV">Judges 1</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.2.NIV">Judges 2</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.53.NIV">Psalm 53</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.7-8.NIV">Proverbs 13:7-8</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.9.NIV">John 9</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 1-2: Watching the video on the book of Judges will prepare you for what you will be reading over the next ten days from the book of Judges. These first two chapters summarize what is coming. Remember that God told the people to drive out the people currently living in the Promised Land because of their ungodly practices, but Israel didn't do it. The rest of the book shows the results of that disobedience.</p>
        <p>Psalm 53: This Psalm is almost identical to Psalm 14, and they likely were alternative versions of the same song.</p>
        <p>John 9: This story is one of my favorites in the Gospels. I especially love verses 24-27. They quiz the man who now can see about who Jesus is. And he doesn't have a theological answer. He just knows that he was blind and now he can see! He even begins to mock the religious leaders by the end of verse 27.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr16">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?105</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 17</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.3.NIV">Judges 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.4.NIV">Judges 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.54.NIV">Psalm 54</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.9-10.NIV">Proverbs 13:9-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.10.NIV">John 10</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 3-4: There are six primary judges talked about in the book. We read of the first primary judges with some very bloody stories. The stories are brief and the people respond pretty well. It only gets worse from here.</p>
        <p>John 10: There are seven "I AM" statement of Jesus in the book of John. Chapter 10 gives us two more. He said "I am the door" (vv. 7, 9), and "I am the good shepherd (vv. 11. 14). If using a Bible with physical pages, underline these "I AM" statements. It helps point the way through the book.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr17">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?106</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 18</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.5.NIV">Judges 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.6.NIV">Judges 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.11.NIV">Proverbs 13:11</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 5-6: After Deborah's song (chapter 5), the people are at peace for 40 years (one generation), and then the cycle begins again. We are introduced to the first of the three judges with longer stories: Gideon. By the end of the chapter Gideon is "putting out a fleece" to test the Lord. Out of His kindness, God answers, but the test wasn't needed. God told Gideon exactly what He wanted. Gideon just lacked the faith and follow through to do it. We really shouldn't look at "putting out a fleece" as an appropriate way to test God's will for us. Gideon's example here is not positive and shouldn't be imitated.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 13:11 - Even back in ancient days, people longed to get rich quick. Not much has changed.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr18">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?107</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 19</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
              <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.7.NIV">Judges 7</a></li>
              <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.8.NIV">Judges 8</a></li>
              <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.12-14.NIV">Proverbs 13:12-14</a></li>
          </ul>

          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Judges 7-8: Notice the stark contrast between the battle in Judges 7 with the battle in Judges 8. In Judges 7, the Lord is clearly getting the glory for the battle as the army was reduced from 32,000 to 300 men. And God's name is all over the chapter. Compare that to chapter 8, when God is hardly mentioned and the portrayal of Gideon is hardly attractive. </p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr19">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?108</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 20</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.9.NIV">Judges 9</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.10.NIV">Judges 10</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.55.1-11.NIV">Psalm 55:1-11</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.15-16.NIV">Proverbs 13:15-16</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.11.NIV">John 11</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 9: This is the sad story of Gideon's son Abimelech. We know from 8:24 that Gideon's name is also Jerubbaal. This is about a violent grab for power.</p>
        <p>Judges 10: This chapter tells us about the sixth and seventh judges of the book: Tola and Jair. There is a cycle throughout the book. Look for it as you read about each judge: 1) sin - 2) oppression - 3) repentance - 4) deliverance - 5) peace. They go through this cycle over and over, and never seem to learn.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr20">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?109</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 21</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.11.NIV">Judges 11</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.12.NIV">Judges 12</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.55.12-23.NIV">Psalm 55:12-23</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.17-19.NIV">Proverbs 13:17-19</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.12.NIV">John 12</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 11-12: The story of Jephthah is tragic. God used him, but he wasn't a godly judge for the nation. One of the most tragic stories in the Old Testament ends chapter 11. It may be helpful to know in Old Testament days in Israel, animals commonly stayed in the house during the winter. As you entered the door, there was a place for animals and then a few steps up into the living area. In other words, likely Jephthah assumed an animal would come out of the door first. It is also possible that he was so influenced by the culture around him that he was willing to sacrifice a human. Regardless of his intention, it is a tragic two chapters.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr21">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?110</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 22</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/RUfh_wOsauk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.13.NIV">Judges 13</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.14.NIV">Judges 14</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.56.NIV">Psalm 56</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.20-23.NIV">Proverbs 13:20-23</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.13.NIV">John 13</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 13-14: We finally get to the best known judge (and the one with the worst character). We read about him today and tomorrow. The cycle has been the same through the book: sin - oppression - repentance - deliverance - peace. They go through this cycle over and over, and never seem to learn. Chapter 13 is the longest introduction to a judge we have in the entire book. Clearly, Samson is going to be a major character in the narrative of the book.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 13:20 - This verse is an ancient reminder of the importance of choosing the right friends for both students and adults. The value of godly friendship has lifelong and eternal implications. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr22">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?111</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 23</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.15.NIV">Judges 15</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.16.NIV">Judges 16</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.57.NIV">Psalm 57</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.13.24-25.NIV">Proverbs 13:24-25</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.14.NIV">John 14</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 15-16: There are ten total feats of strength by Samson and eight of them are in these two chapters. These chapters contain some of the best known stories of Samson.</p>
        <p>Psalm 57: This is a great Psalm to remember to turn back to. It is a great example of how to pray and praise even when we suffer and trouble surrounds us.</p>
        <p>John 14: As you read this, remember Jesus will be arrested in a matter of hours and on the cross within 12 to 15 hours. It puts a context of what Jesus was thinking, and what He was preparing his disciples for.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr23">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?112</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 24</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.17.NIV">Judges 17</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.18.NIV">Judges 18</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.58.NIV">Psalm 58</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.1-2.NIV">Proverbs 14:1-2</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.15.NIV">John 15</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 17-18: Things don't get better after Samson. We see a repeated phrase in the last five chapters about Israel not having a king and everyone doing what is right in their own eyes. If you are using a Bible with paper pages, underline that repeated phrase. In many ways, it is the theme of the book. You will read it today in 17:6 and 18:1</p>
        <p>John 15: Jesus continues His "final words" to His disciples before His arrest, trials, and crucifixion. Read it in that light.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr24">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?113</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 25</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.19.NIV">Judges 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.20.NIV">Judges 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.3-4.NIV">Proverbs 14:3-4</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 19-20: The last three chapters are very disturbing. It is hard to believe how hard and fast they turned from God. May this book be a reminder to us that we must follow after God intentionally, humbly, and continuously.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 14:4 - Life with no kids is simpler. Coming to church without being involved in serving or a community group keeps it neat and clean. But I think God has called all of us to "run to the mess" and be part of people's lives - even though it is hard and messy.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr25">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?114</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 26</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JDG.21.NIV">Judges 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.5-6.NIV">Proverbs 14:5-6</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Judges 21: With the potential loss of an entire tribe, the people save the tribe of Benjamin through less than righteous means. The book ends with the repeated editorial on the moral anarchy of God's people.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr26">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?115</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 27</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/0h1eoBeR4Jk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/RUT.1.NIV">Ruth 1</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/RUT.2.NIV">Ruth 2</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.59.NIV">Psalm 59</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.7-8.NIV">Proverbs 14:7-8</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.16.NIV">John 16</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ruth 1-2: Be sure to watch the video on the summary of the book of Ruth. It will help you understand this small Old Testament book.</p>
        <p>Psalm 59: The book of Psalms often have prayers from David asking God to protect him from his enemies. His enemies were trying to kill him, and David was asking for protection and justice. It can be difficult to know how to read, pray, and apply these types of Psalms since most of us don't have enemies out to kill us, and we aren't looking for God to deliver eternal justice to those with whom we don't get along. Perhaps the best way to read, pray, and apply these types of Psalms is to realize that the devil is our ultimate enemy who is out to defeat us and hurt us in every way possible. Consider praying these types of Psalms with that in mind. It may help you read them in a fresh way.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr27">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?116</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 28</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/RUT.3.NIV">Ruth 3</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/RUT.4.NIV">Ruth 4</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.60.NIV">Psalm 60</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.9-10.NIV">Proverbs 14:9-10</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.17.NIV">John 17</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Ruth 3-4: This provides the third and fourth scene of this book (Chapter 3 - Ruth at the threshing floor; Chapter 4 - Boaz redeems Ruth). But the essential part of the book is the ending - which ties this story to the Messiah. Ruth and Boaz are the great-grandparents of King David, in the line of the Messiah.</p>
        <p>Psalm 60: For the context of this Psalm, you could read 2 Samuel 8:1-14.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr28">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?117</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 29</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/QJOju5Dw0V0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.1.NIV">1 Samuel 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.2.NIV">1 Samuel 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.61.NIV">Psalm 61</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.11-12.NIV">Proverbs 14:11-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.18.NIV">John 18</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 1-2: We are introduced to Samuel, Israel's last judge. Be sure to watch the video. It will help you see the flow of the book before you begin to read it. </p>
        <p>John 18: There really are two trials of Jesus: His Jewish trial and His Roman trial. His Jewish trial is a religious trial. The Roman trial was before Pilate. The Jews wanted Jesus killed, but they wanted the Romans to do it. So they asked for, and received, Pilate's help in seeing Jesus crucified.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr29">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?118</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>April 30</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.3.NIV">1 Samuel 3</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.4.NIV">1 Samuel 4</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.62.NIV">Psalm 62</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.13-14.NIV">Proverbs 14:13-14</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.19.NIV">John 19</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 4: As you read 1 & 2 Samuel over the next few weeks, you will see the Ark of the Covenant in many of the stories. It was meant to be an article in the holy of holies, and the people began to use it as a "good luck charm" when going to war. It was a misuse of a holy item God meant for a specific purpose. The phrase in verse 11: "The ark of God was captured" is a shocking statement. It was meant to be a meeting place between the high priest and God once a year. And now it was so misused, it became a spoil of war. </p>
        <p>Psalm 62: This Psalm is a great song to remind God's people of His care especially when they face opposition from people with power and wealth. It is a great reminder for us all: power belongs to God. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Apr30">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?119</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
