<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Reading</title>
    <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
    <link>https://newheights.org</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

    <!-- <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/.NIV"></a></li> -->
    <!-- <iframe src="https://youtu.be/JqOqJlFF_eU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe> -->
    <!-- youtube.com/embed/id -->
    <item>
      <title>September 1</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/oE9qqW1-BkU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.5.NIV">Isaiah 5</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.6.NIV">Isaiah 6</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.111.NIV">Psalm 111</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.14.NIV">Proverbs 22:14</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PHP.1.NIV">Philippians 1</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 5-6: Today's reading includes one of the most beautiful pictures of God's throne room as seen through Isaiah's eyes. This is Isaiah's call scene, in the year King Uzziah died which is about 740 BC (about 135 years before the fall of Judah to the Babylonians). Isaiah's mission will be calling the nation of Judah to repent, but they will not. Jesus quotes Isaiah 6:9 in Matthew 13 to explain why He speaks in parables. Similar to Isaiah He's calling people to repent, and they refuse.</p>
          <p>Philippians 1: The Letter to the Philippians is one of Paul's most encouraging letters. Philippi was the city with the first church Paul ever planted in Europe (read Acts 16 for whole story). Notice that the words "joy", "rejoice", and "confidence" are used a lot in this small letter. They make up the main themes of the letter.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep1">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?243</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 2</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.7.NIV">Isaiah 7</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.8.NIV">Isaiah 8</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.112.NIV">Psalm 112</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.15.NIV">Proverbs 22:15</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PHP.2.NIV">Philippians 2</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 7-8: Chapter 7 is confusing as it will deal with three kings with unique  names. Here's the kings for you: Rezin the King of Syria (to the northeast of the promised land) and Pekah the king of Israel (remember Israel had a civil war and split into two countries Judah and Israel). Rezin and Pekah are the northern two nations that border Judah and are threatening King Ahaz of Judah. In this story we get one of the most powerful prophecies in the entire OT. We get the promise of Immanuel (God with us.); the circumstances reveal that when God's people are at the lowest, He will show up.</p>
          <p>Philippians 2: This chapter was traditionally known as a hymn or song of Christ. It highlights Christ's humility, and Paul will use the lyrics as the example of how a Christ follower treats others.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep2">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?244</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 3</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.9.NIV">Isaiah 9</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.10.NIV">Isaiah 10</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.113.NIV">Psalm 113</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.16.NIV">Proverbs 22:16</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PHP.3.NIV">Philippians 3</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 9-10: Chapter 9 will give light and hope in the harsh circumstances surrounding chapters 7-8. Today you will read about more of the promises of the Messiah coming, and these are given 750 years before Jesus is born. God responds to present pain with a future hope. With this promise God will then describe His judgement on the unjust nations.</p>
          <p>Psalm 113: Notice when you read how God is described as high up (multiple times in this short Psalm), but also notice how He cares for the lowly.</p>
          <p>Philippians 3: Paul will describe why righteousness only comes from Christ. He is confronting a belief that in order to be saved by the God of the Jewish people, a person had to become Jewish (the group who believed this were called Judaizers). Paul is saying we're saved apart from anything we could "do" or anything we were born into. It's all about faith in Jesus.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep3">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?245</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 4</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.11.NIV">Isaiah 11</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.12.NIV">Isaiah 12</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.114.NIV">Psalm 114</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.17-19.NIV">Proverbs 22:17-19</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PHP.4.NIV">Philippians 4</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 11-12: When you read about Jesse, remember that he was David's father. Therefore, the stump of Jesse refers to the Davidic lines, and when you read about David's line think "king" or "messiah" (annointed king). Isaiah 11 refers to the fact that the line of David seems like it will be cut down, but a little shoot will grow, and this will be the promised Messianic king. When He arrives, He will change everything.</p>
          <p>Philippians 4: Paul concludes this letter of joy, humility, and confidence with a call for resolved conflict in the church (Christ's examples gives the picture of conflict resolution).</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep4">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?246</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 5</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.13.NIV">Isaiah 13</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.14.NIV">Isaiah 14</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.20-21.NIV">Proverbs 22:20-21</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 13-14: The next 14 chapters of Isaiah will give God's judgement of the other nations surrounding Israel/Judah. While it seems odd to us, it's important to remember that God has spent the first 13 chapters judging Israel/Judah's corruption, and He is revealing His heart of justice. The nations have been dealing with people horribly, and God is revealing that He will deal with them. What's powerful is His justice will pave the way for the future hope.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep5">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?247</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 6</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.15.NIV">Isaiah 15</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.16.NIV">Isaiah 16</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.22-23.NIV">Proverbs 22:22-23</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 15-16: Moab is a nation to the east of Judah. They have a long standing history with God's people all the way back to Genesis 19. Much of the history is fraught with conflict, but the destruction they face causes the Lord's heart to break for them.</p>
          <p>Proverbs 22:22-23: A reminder that God has a huge heart for the poor and less fortunate. When we treat the less fortunate well we are demonstrating God's heart.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep6">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?248</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 7</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/pXTXlDxQsvc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.17.NIV">Isaiah 17</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.18.NIV">Isaiah 18</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.115.NIV">Psalm 115</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.24-25.NIV">Proverbs 22:24-25</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/COL.1.NIV">Colossians 1</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 17-18: The next of the oracles of the nations is Syria (called Damascus the capital city) to be judged. Syria falls in 732 BC to Assyria fulfilling all of the prophecies of this chapter. When reading this chapter remember back to chapter 7 when Syria is plotting to destroy Judah, it will help you as you see the conclusion to their story.</p>
          <p>Colossians 1: Colossae was a city in Asia Minor (or modern day Turkey). Paul is writing to the church describing who Jesus is. Verses 15-23 give one of the most clear and succinct descriptions of Jesus' nature in the entire Bible; He is totally and completely God; He's not a half-god or Demigod; He is the creator who stands above His creation and dies for them. It's worth memorizing.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep7">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?249</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 8</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.19.NIV">Isaiah 19</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.20.NIV">Isaiah 20</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.116.NIV">Psalm 116</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.26-27.NIV">Proverbs 22:26-27</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/COL.2.NIV">Colossians 2</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 19-20: The next of the oracles of the nations will be about Egypt. God's people have had a history with Egypt all the way back to Genesis. Most recently, Judah looked to Egypt for protection against Assyria; Egypt was the very nation who had enslaved the Jewish people before. God, who has the power to save and judge will judge Egypt for their folly demonstrating who Judah should've looked to all along, the LORD Himself.</p>
          <p>Colossians 2: Laodicea was close to Colossae, and both churches were closely connected, so Paul will connect both in this letter. Paul's occasion for writing this letter is to combat false teaching. There was a false teaching that claimed there was a "mystery of God" that only the false teachers knew. Paul is writing to say that mystery of God is Christ and what He did for us and that He is with us. Paul is emphatic that anything beyond Christ is a lie and false.</p>
          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep8">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?250</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 9</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.21.NIV">Isaiah 21</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.22.NIV">Isaiah 22</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.117.NIV">Psalm 117</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.22.28-29.NIV">Proverbs 22:28-29</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/COL.3.NIV">Colossians 3</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 21-22: The next series of Oracles will be about the nations of Babylon (who becomes the next empire in the world), to Edom (Judah's neighbors to the south), to Arabia, and then turns the judgement to Jerusalem! (God's chosen city). This is shocking, because God has judged the nations, but now He is judging His own people for looking to these sinful nations to save them instead of being God's light and city on the hill. When reading 21:9, this promise will be further explained in Revelation 18:1-3. These promises have an eternal component to them.</p>
          <p>Colossians 3: Paul switches from the theoretical ideas of chapters 1 & 2 to the practical in chapters 3 & 4. If Jesus is the supreme ruler of creation who conquered death, how should we live? He will give examples of unity in the family and broader society. Pay close attention to the phrase "put to death" and "clothe." This is metaphoric of the ideas Paul is getting at. It's all about changing how we think and what we value.</p>
          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep9">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?251</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 10</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.23.NIV">Isaiah 23</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.24.NIV">Isaiah 24</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.118.1-14.NIV">Psalm 118:1-14</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.1-3.NIV">Proverbs 23:1-3</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/COL.4.NIV">Colossians 4</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 23-24: Today you will read about the next two nations judged by the  LORD, but it will lead to God judging the whole earth for their injustice. This is the climactic and final judgement, but it's building to a hope in the coming chapters. A theme in Isaiah is judgement for the nations injustice, but that judgement paves the way for the hope of the nations, the Messiah. As you read, know God judges the nations but is orchestrating a hope beyond the judgement.</p>
          <p>Colossians 4: The final practical instructions are given by Paul to the Colossians, notice that Paul starts with prayer and then moves to interaction with outsiders. Paul understands that connection with the Lord leads to care and opportunities with those who don't know Jesus. It's a great example for you and me.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep10">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?252</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 11</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/No7Nq6IX23c" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.25.NIV">Isaiah 25</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.26.NIV">Isaiah 26</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.118.15-29.NIV">Psalm 118:15-29</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.4-5.NIV">Proverbs 23:4-5</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TH.1.NIV">1 Thessalonians 1</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 25-26: Chapter 25 switches perspectives from God speaking to Isaiah speaking for himself. Isaiah shares his praise because God's judgement will lead to hope. The very people who are being judged are the ones creating violence, destruction, and oppression. When God judges, it leads to hope and restoration for His people. Isaiah celebrates God's righteous judgement and how He will fight for those who have been voiceless to these violent nations. It leads to God extending His love to all nations. It's an example of another theme in the book; judgement will lead to restoration and hope.</p>
          <p>1 Thessalonians 1: Thessalonica was a capital city of Macedonia (a prominent Roman province); it was a huge city with over 100,000 people. This was a significant ministry opportunity for Paul (read Acts 17 for the whole story). The church was doing well, but struggled with the deaths of some of its most beloved members. Paul writes to encourage and clarify the truth about death and Jesus' 2nd coming.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep11">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?253</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 12</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.27.NIV">Isaiah 27</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.28.NIV">Isaiah 28</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.6-8.NIV">Proverbs 23:6-8</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 27-28: Some helpful hints for chapter 27-28, the word Leviathan is traditionally thought of as a dragon-like creature. It's mostly associated with evil in the OT. The NT will refer to Isaiah 27 in Revelation 20 about this very promise; it refers to God redeeming His people. The other hint is to pay close attention to Isaiah 28:16. The Cornerstone was the most important stone in buildings in the ancient world; they set the foundation for the rest of the building. God is using the metaphor to describe the Messianic King coming who will be a sure foundation for the people of God. It will be a promise reverberated throughout the rest of the Bible.</p>
          <p>Proverbs 23:6-8: Notice when you read verse 6 the line "begrudging host". In Hebrew, the same line is "the man whose eyes are evil." Their eyes are locked on to their own selfish desires. Essentially this proverb is highlighting the importance of fellowship with someone whose eyes, heart, and motivations are one of generosity. When a person is greedy, everyone else pays for it.</p>
          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep12">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?254</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 13</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.29.NIV">Isaiah 29</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.30.NIV">Isaiah 30</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.9-11.NIV">Proverbs 23:9-11</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 29-30: When you read Ariel, it either means "Lion of God" Or "Altar of God". It refers to Jerusalem- and this section is referencing the destruction of Jerusalem which is 145 years away. The people claim to follow God, but it's all for show; their hearts are far from His.</p>
          <p>Proverbs 23:9-11: This Proverb highlights how God is the redeemer of the less fortunate. Entering the fields of the fatherless (or "orphan") had to do with taking advantage of the orphan by taking their resources from them for your own gain. It's a reminder that God has a huge heart for those who are marginalized.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep13">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?255</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 14</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.31.NIV">Isaiah 31</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.32.NIV">Isaiah 32</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.1-8.NIV">Psalm 119:1-8</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.12.NIV">Proverbs 23:12</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TH.2.NIV">1 Thessalonians 2</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 31-32: Chapter 32 gives another promise of a King who will reign in righteousness; it's another promise of the Messianic King. This King will not rule like the current kings who oppress and enact injustice, this King will rule in a way that leads people into a full relationship with the LORD. It's powerful when you understand these promises are given 750 years before Jesus is born (for context the United States has been an independent nation for less than 250 years.) These promises are long before the coming of Jesus, but reveal how Jesus was always the central promise of God.</p>
          <p>Psalm 119:1-8: This is the longest Psalm in the Bible (and the longest chapter). It celebrates God giving His Word. It is an acrostic poem meaning the beginning of each verse starts with the next letter in the Hebrew alphabet.</p>
          <p>1 Thessalonians 2: Paul highlights that the Thessalonians endurance through suffering and persecution was a validation of their authentic faith. How we respond in suffering will bring out the quality of our faith.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep14">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?256</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 15</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.33.NIV">Isaiah 33</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.34.NIV">Isaiah 34</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.9-16.NIV">Psalm 119:9-16</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.13-14.NIV">Proverbs 23:13-14</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TH.3.NIV">1 Thessalonians 3</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 33-34: For all of these nations God is judging, the nation that has been His tool is Assyria to enact His justice. Even they will be judged. Chapters 33-34 are building to the climax of the judgement. When all is said and done, the two endings for these nations are either judgement or salvation. The last twenty chapters have been the judgement with some hopeful passages, soon it will switch to more hopeful passages with judgement sprinkled in there.</p>
          <p>1 Thessalonians 3: It's powerful when we see Paul's genuine care for the people he serves; we see this in chapter 3. These people in the Scriptures are real people with emotions like you and me. As you read notice Paul's genuine love and concern for this church he serves.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep15">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?257</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 16</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.35.NIV">Isaiah 35</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.36.NIV">Isaiah 36</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.17-24.NIV">Psalm 119:17-24</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.15-16.NIV">Proverbs 23:15-16</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TH.4.NIV">1 Thessalonians 4</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 35-36: Chapter 36 has a shift from poetry to a narrative block for the next  three chapters. This story parallels the account in 2 Kings 18. It brings up all of the themes of the last 14 chapters in narrative form through the lens of King Hezekiah. Remember a huge theme is to not look to any earthly power for rescue but to the LORD Himself. This will play out through Hezekiah's story.</p>
          <p>Psalm 119:17-24 - The psalmist celebrates that even God's rules lead to life. God's commands were not meant to be merely restrictive, they were given so we can enjoy life as it's meant to be enjoyed.</p>
          <p>1 Thessalonians 4: Verse 13 is powerful for those of us who have had a loved one pass away. Paul's point is that because of Christ's victory over death, we can grieve with hope.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep16">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?258</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 17</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.37.NIV">Isaiah 37</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.38.NIV">Isaiah 38</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.25-32.NIV">Psalm 119:25-32</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.17-18.NIV">Proverbs 23:17-18</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TH.5.NIV">1 Thessalonians 5</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 37-38: The empire of Assyria is trying to destroy Judah (the northern kingdom of Israel has already been destroyed), but King Hezekiah seeks the LORD's help. This is the only time up to this point that Sennacherib did not capture a city that he was attempting to capture. God was with Judah and protected them. We see another example of God's protection with Hezekiah's health; both of these events highlight the theme that God's leaders and people should look to Him for help and rescue over anything else.</p>
          <p>1 Thessalonians 5: The Day of the Lord is a very important idea and phrase from the OT (especially in the prophets). It reveals God's judgement and justice for those who oppress and bring violence, and it's a hopeful day for those who trust in the Lord. The point Paul will make is that we live in light of this "Day". We live each day with eternity in mind.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep17">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?259</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 18</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/kbPBDKOn1cc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.39.NIV">Isaiah 39</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.40.NIV">Isaiah 40</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.33-40.NIV">Psalm 119:33-40</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.19-21.NIV">Proverbs 23:19-21</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2TH.1.NIV">2 Thessalonians 1</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 39-40: In chapter 39 we see the downfall of King Hezekiah. After the defeat of Assyria, who had returned home to battle the Babylonians who were rising up, the Babylonians come and win over Hezekiah with flattery. This will demonstrate Hezekiah's pride and his heart's belief that he saved Judah instead of the LORD. It leads to dire consequences for Judah- the very nation that flattered them will carry the next generation into captivity in Babylon. Notice the tone shift of chapter 40 as well, it shifts from judgement to comfort; it also jumps into the future with a message for the people after their time in Babylon.</p>
          <p>2 Thessalonians 1: Paul writes another letter to the church in Thessalonica. The theme of Christ's second coming will continue to be a dominant theme. The Thessalonians endured some persecution, and Paul will remind them that God sees and there will be justice.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep18">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?260</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 19</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/_TzdEPuqgQg" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.41.NIV">Isaiah 41</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.42.NIV">Isaiah 42</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.22.NIV">Proverbs 23:22</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 41-42: Chapter 42 begins a series of four songs that will be sprinkled throughout the rest of Isaiah called the Servant Songs.
            These are songs celebrating the coming acts of the Messianic King. Notice that Isaiah compares the futility of idols to this Servant King who will come; this King is far better than anything we can make ourselves.</p>
          <p>Proverbs 23:22 - A Proverb rooted in the 5th Commandment from Exodus 20. The 5th command is the only command with a promise attached to it. When we honor our parents our lives are better.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep19">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?261</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 20</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.43.NIV">Isaiah 43</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.44.NIV">Isaiah 44</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.23.NIV">Proverbs 23.23</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 43-44: Today's reading highlights that the LORD is God and apart from Him there is no other. This is meant to demonstrate the futility of anything else people could look to for salvation and peace. God is the creator, and Judah's idolatry (and all idolatry) seems so foolish in comparison to the God who creates us, sustains us, and cares for us.</p>
          <p>Proverbs 23:23: Wisdom and truth are valuable, the author will highlight they are worth buying and not getting rid of. If you want to live a full and abundant life it doesn't start with materials or wealth, it starts with the wisdom rooted in the fear of the LORD.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep20">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?262</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 21</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.45.NIV">Isaiah 45</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.46.NIV">Isaiah 46</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.41-48.NIV">Psalm 119:41-48</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.24-25.NIV">Proverbs 23:24-25</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2TH.2.NIV">2 Thessalonians 2</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 45-46: God appoints Cyrus the Great (Ruler of Persia) as the one who will help restore Jerusalem. This is 150 years before Cyrus is born. Josephus the ancient historian highlights that Cyrus was so impressed with this prophecy that he sought to honor the promise of the LORD. This is all meant to reveal that empires will rise and fall, but it's the LORD standing above them sovereignly ruling.</p>
          <p>2 Thessalonians 2: Paul is responding to a false teaching that claimed the Day of the Lord had already happened. Paul is asserting it has not, and he's encouraging the Church to continue to stand firm. The Day of the Lord will begin with rebellion and lead to the Man of Lawlessness (elsewhere known as the Anti-Christ, the one who will lead people away from Jesus).</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep21">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?263</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 22</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.47.NIV">Isaiah 47</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.48.NIV">Isaiah 48</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.49-56.NIV">Psalm 119:49-56</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.26-28.NIV">Proverbs 23:26-28</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2TH.3.NIV">2 Thessalonians 3</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 47-48: Babylon is symbolic of all the corruption of the world, and it metaphorically represents the people who try and glorify themselves. This current Babylon will be dealt with and God will redeem and free His people. In the ancient world when a nation conquered another, it was believed that the conquering nations god defeated the god of the losing nation. The LORD is stating the gods of Babylon did not win, the LORD orchestrated it all, and He caused Babylon to rise and He's the one who makes them fall.</p>
          <p>2 Thessalonians 3: Paul's warning against idleness is powerful. Since we don't know when Christ is coming back, we should live every moment being ready; idleness is the antithesis to this idea. Therefore, Paul gives pictures of what it looks like to live productively waiting for Christ to return.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep22">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?264</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 23</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/7RoqnGcEjcs" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.49.NIV">Isaiah 49</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.50.NIV">Isaiah 50</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.57-64.NIV">Psalm 119:57-64</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.23.29-35.NIV">Proverbs 23:29-35</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TI.1.NIV">1 Timothy 1</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 49-50: Isaiah 49:1-6 is the 2nd of the Servant Songs of Isaiah. Each gives a different aspect of the promise of the Messiah. Notice verse 6 particularly, because it describes the mission of the Messiah. The mission is to restore Israel, so that the Messiah can be known by all the nations. The 3rd Servant Song is in Chapter 50 verse 4-7 (notice it changes to 1st person); this song compares the failure of God's people to the obedience of the Messianic King.</p>
          <p>1 Timothy 1: Paul is writing to his young disciple Timothy about how Timothy can lead the church in Ephesus away from some false teachers. Paul is writing about how the Gospel is lived out practically in the Church. Notice how starting in verse 12, Paul recounts his faith story. It brings the letter to the central theme of the gospel. It's an amazing testimony of God's grace.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep23">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?265</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 24</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.51.NIV">Isaiah 51</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.52.NIV">Isaiah 52</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.65-72.NIV">Psalm 119:65-72</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.1-2.NIV">Proverbs 24:1-2</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TI.2.NIV">1 Timothy 2</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 51-52: Today highlights why Israel should follow the Messiah. Through the Messiah, all the nations will be blessed, there will be a new Eden, and they will be vindicated. This leads to the 4th Servant Song, which is bridged between chapter 52 & 53. This is what is traditionally known as the Suffering Servant Song. This song highlights the suffering the Messiah will endure to redeem humanity. Remember as you read that this promise is given 750 years before Jesus is born; it's incredible to see God's plan unfolding before the very events happen.</p>
          <p>1 Timothy 2: Paul goes from the message of the gospel to the action of the gospel. Remember when he says to pray for kings, these are kings who are killing and torturing Christians. The gospel even then calls us to live differently.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep24">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?266</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 25</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.53.NIV">Isaiah 53</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.54.NIV">Isaiah 54</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.73-80.NIV">Psalm 119:73-80</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.3-4.NIV">Proverbs 24:3-4</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TI.3.NIV">1 Timothy 3</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 53-54: As you read Isaiah 53, it's powerful to compare the song to the four Gospel accounts of Jesus' crucifixion. The Gospels each quote this passage as the chief promise of God dealing with our sin through the Messianic King. This sacrifice leads to God extending His compassion to all in chapter 54. Remember this was all foretold 750 years before the birth of Christ.</p>
          <p>1 Timothy 3: From how an individual lives in chapter 2, Paul transitions to the structure of the Church in chapter 3. In order for the Church to be healthy, there needs to be an organizational structure. The people who lead need to have character; this was radical in the 1st century when you had Nero Caesar leading as a very maniacal narcissistic leader. Jesus flips leadership upside down.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep25">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?267</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 26</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.55.NIV">Isaiah 55</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.56.NIV">Isaiah 56</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.5-6.NIV">Proverbs 24:5-6</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 55-56:  In the first few verses of chapter 55, read John 7:37-39 as well. Jesus will refer to Himself as the waters everyone should come to. In essence, He's saying He is the fulfillment of these promises. Chapter 56 is God's plans extended to every nation which is a fulfillment of the promises given to Abram/Abraham in Genesis 12 (through Abram/Abraham all the nations of the world will be blessed).</p>
          <p>Proverbs 24:5-6: The proverb highlights how wisdom is more powerful than any force or might a person can conjure up.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep26">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?268</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 27</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.57.NIV">Isaiah 57</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.58.NIV">Isaiah 58</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.7.NIV">Proverbs 24:7</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 57-58: You will read about what real repentance is and what God wants in repentance. Fasting in the ancient world was often a very public activity, and if a person wasn't careful it could become just for show and the approval of others. God desires a truly contrite heart.</p>
          <p>Proverbs 24:7: The city gate was where "court" and commerce was held in the ancient world. Because the fool doesn't have wisdom, they are quiet with the leaders at the gate because wisdom was out of reach for them.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep27">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?269</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 28</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.59.NIV">Isaiah 59</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.60.NIV">Isaiah 60</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.81-88.NIV">Psalm 119:81-88</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.8.NIV">Proverbs 24:8</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TI.4.NIV">1 Timothy 4</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 59-60: Chapter 60 highlights when God finally deals with sin and brokenness. You will find a quote in Revelation 21-22 in Isaiah 60. Notice all the nations that were being judged in the first half of the book are being invited into worshipping the LORD. It's a powerful picture of how God's judgement leads to future hope.</p>
          <p>1 Timothy 4: Paul has demonstrated what a faithful person looks like in the preceding chapters, now he will now highlight what a false teacher and a faithless person looks like. Timothy is young, so to give these instructions Paul encourages his boldness and example to church in Ephesus.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep28">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?270</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 29</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.61.NIV">Isaiah 61</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.62.NIV">Isaiah 62</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.89-96.NIV">Psalm 119:89-96</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.9-10.NIV">Proverbs 24:9-10</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TI.5.NIV">1 Timothy 5</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 61-62: Chapter 61:1-4 is what the Messiah will announce when He arrives. Luke records Jesus going into the synagogue and reading Isaiah 61. He then proclaims that He is the fulfillment of this announcement, meaning He is the Promised Messianic King. Remember this promise is given 750 years before the birth of Jesus.</p>
          <p>1 Timothy 5: Paul now continues to give specific examples of how the gospel should look in our lives. Everything from one on one relationships, to employees, to how to rebuke people are all covered. Ultimately they all highlight what a healthy community following Jesus should look like.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep29">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?271</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>September 30</title>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[ <hr>
          <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
          <br>
          <br>
          <ul>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.63.NIV">Isaiah 63</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ISA.64.NIV">Isaiah 64</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.119.97-104.NIV">Psalm 119:97-104</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.24.11-12.NIV">Proverbs 24:11-12</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1TI.6.NIV">1 Timothy 6</a></li>
          </ul>
          <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
          <p>Isaiah 63-64: Chapters 63 now portray the warrior Messiah. The Messiah will come to serve and suffer for the people, but He will also come to fight for the people. This section highlights Him fighting the injustice and wickedness of the people who rebel against the Lord. This is where we get the Grapes of Wrath  phrase due to the Messiah treading the Winepress of His wrath.</p>
          <p>1 Timothy 6: Paul wraps up by being very clear about how to identify and deal with false teachers. This issue was rampant in Ephesus, and Paul wants to equip and encourage Timothy and the church as a whole.</p>

          <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Sep30">
        ]]>
      </description>
      <link>https://newheights.org/?272</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
