<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Daily Reading</title>
  <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
  <link>https://newheights.org</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

  <item>
    <title>January 1</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KOUV7mWDI34" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.1.NIV">Genesis 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.2.NIV">Genesis 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.1.NIV">Psalm 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.1.1-6.NIV">Proverbs 1:1-6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.1.NIV">Matthew 1</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Day 1, let’s do this!</p>
        <p>Three things for you to know:</p>
        <p>1. If you don’t have the <a href="http://onelink.to/6sva4s">YouVersion app</a>, download it! We love this Bible app because as you highlight verses or make notes - it will stay with you whether you open the Bible through this reading plan or in YouVersion. The Bible links we provide will automatically take you to YouVersion, if you have the app.</p>
        <p>2. Somedays, you’ll notice a short video. Don’t skip it! It will give you a great overview of what we’re reading.</p>
        <p>3. 🔵 The Blue Dot. Consider this a heads up for all you checklist lovers! Next to each Daily Reading is a blue dot, indicating you haven’t read that day yet. Once you open that day, you can’t hit “not read” and get the blue dot back.</p>
        <p>Our hope is that God blesses you as we dive into this journey of reading through the Bible in a year!</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan1">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?1</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>


  <item>
    <title>January 2</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Dv4-n6OYGI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.3.NIV">Genesis 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.4.NIV">Genesis 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.2.NIV">Psalm 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.1.7-9.NIV">Proverbs 1:7-9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.2.NIV">Matthew 2</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Curious how the Daily Reading Plan is laid out?<br>
        - Seven days a week, we’ll read two chapters from the Old Testament and a short section from Proverbs.<br>
        - Monday-Friday, we’ll also read a chapter from the New Testament and a chapter of Old Testament Poetry.<br>
        - With less reading on the weekends, it’s a great time to catch up on reading from the week.</p>
        <p>What’s with all the videos?<br>
        For starters, we think they’re awesome! But, you won't usually have a video everyday. Since we’re starting four books of the Bible this week, we included a video for the first four days. If you think they’re as awesome as we do, you find more at <a href="https://TheBibleProject.com">TheBibleProject.com</a>.</p>
        <p>How can I take notes as I read?<br>
        Get the <a href="http://onelink.to/6sva4s">YouVersion app</a>! It’s our favorite Bible app for this reason! As you highlight verses or make notes - it will stay with you whether you open the Bible through this reading plan or in YouVersion. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan2">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?2</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933asdf85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 3</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/j9phNEaPrv8" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.5.NIV">Genesis 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.6.NIV">Genesis 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.3.NIV">Psalm 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.1.10-19.NIV">Proverbs 1:10-19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.3.NIV">Matthew 3</a></li></ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 5: It can be shocking to see the claim that people lived hundreds of years. Is that really true? There are various interpretations that don't take the number literally. But none seem very convincing. It is best to take the numbers at face value, and assume something changed in the cosmology of the earth with the flood (Genesis 6-8) resulting in a rapid decline in longevity of life. Regardless of one's interpretation, it is clear these people actually lived and actually died, moving us generation by generation closer to the coming of Christ (the entire point of human history).</p>
        <p>By the way, we recommend purchasing a good Study Bible or two. It will answer 90% of the questions you have when you read something that is confusing. We recommend choosing one or two of these options:</p>
        <ol>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/ESV-Study-Bible-Bibles-Crossway/dp/1433502410">ESV Study Bible</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/NIV-Study-Bible-Hardcover-Letter/dp/0310438926">NIV Study Bible</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/NIV-Zondervan-Study-Bible-Hardcover/dp/0310438330">Zondervan Study Bible</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tyndale-Application-Hardcover-Features-International/dp/1496433831/">Life Application Study Bible</a></li> 
        </ol>
        <p>If you want other suggestions, just let us know.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan3">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?3</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f93323d85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 4</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AzmYV8GNAIM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.7.NIV">Genesis 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.8.NIV">Genesis 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.1.20-23.NIV">Proverbs 1:20-23</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 8: When it says that "God remembered Noah" (8:1), it doesn't mean that God had forgotten about him. In Hebrew, the word "remember" means "to bring to mind."</p>
        <p>Proverbs 1:20-23: In the early chapters of the book of Proverbs, wisdom is often "personified" (it "speaks" as if it were a person). And when the writer says, "My Son" - it is commonly believed to be the writer talking to his child (not "Wisdom" speaking generally).</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan4">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?4</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 5</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.9.NIV">Genesis 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.10.NIV">Genesis 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.1.24-28.NIV">Proverbs 1:24-28</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 9: Everytime you see a rainbow, your mind should go to the promise God made here in Genesis 9. We should all be thankful that He will never flood the entire earth again.</p>
        <p>Genesis 10: Genealogies can be difficult to read because it doesn't always seem important, and because they are usually difficult names to pronounce. Remind yourself, this list has a purpose (one of which is to get us closer to the coming of Christ). To avoid difficult pronunciations, you can use the audio option in the <a href="http://onelink.to/6sva4s">YouVersion app</a> and let a "professional" read you the nearly impossible names. Otherwise, just do your best and give it a try!</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan5">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?5</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 6</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VpbWbyx1008" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.11.NIV">Genesis 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.12.NIV">Genesis 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.4.NIV">Psalm 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.1.29-33.NIV">Proverbs 1:29-33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.4.NIV">Matthew 4</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today: </p>
        <p>Genesis 12: The transition from Genesis 11 to Genesis 12 is a big one. In the first eleven chapters of the book, God is dealing with all mankind. Now, beginning in chapter 12, He focuses on one man and his family, Abram. The rest of the Old Testament will focus on God's relationship with this one family, who will become the nation of Israel. Assuming no generations were skipped (and they likely were), it is at least 2000 years from Adam to Abram, and less than 2000 years from Abram to Jesus. So Genesis 12 is the halfway point of OT history, and a transition from God dealing with all mankind to God focusing on a relationship with one group of people - the Israelites. </p>
        <p>Psalm 4: Note to parents: Psalm 4 ends with an amazing verse that is great to teach children who are afraid of the dark. The Bible is filled with thousands of verses that can impact our daily lives. It is a great idea to highlight these types of verses in your app, or underline them if you are using a physical Bible. They will be easier to find when you come looking for them later. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan6">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?6</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 7</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.13.NIV">Genesis 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.14.NIV">Genesis 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.5.NIV">Psalm 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.2.1-5.NIV">Proverbs 2:1-5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.5.NIV">Matthew 5</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 14: Between God's Promises to Abram (chapter 12) and God's Covenant with Abram (chapter 15), we have two chapters about Abram's nephew, Lot. Notice in chapter 14, we also are introduced to a mysterious character Melchizedek that will be mentioned a few times through the Bible (especially in Hebrews 7).</p>
        <p>Matthew 5: This chapter begins what is known as "The Sermon on the Mount," and contains some of the best-known words of Jesus. As you read, notice how many of them are familiar to you.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan7">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?7</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 8</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.15.NIV">Genesis 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.16.NIV">Genesis 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.6.NIV">Psalm 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.2.6-15.NIV">Proverbs 2:6-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.6.NIV">Matthew 6</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 15: This mysterious chapter is one of the most important chapters in the Old Testament. It contains the Abrahamic Covenant - an everlasting covenant that God promised to His people. As you read this chapter, notice two things: a) v. 13 speaks of the coming slavery in Egypt and even gives the length of time they will be there, and b) Verse 17 talks about the firepot passing between the pieces of the animal. That is how one would make a covenant in ancient times. Two parties would walk between the dead animal to indicate their commitment and willingness to be killed if they didn't fulfill their part of the covenant. What is most important here is that Abram did not pass between the pieces of the animal. In other words, God was the one making the promise - not Abram. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan8">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?8</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 9</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.17.NIV">Genesis 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.18.NIV">Genesis 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.7.NIV">Psalm 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.2.16-22.NIV">Proverbs 2:16-22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.7.NIV">Matthew 7</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 17: If you are new to the Bible, this is a strange chapter - introducing the covenant of circumcision. Some covenants have signs associated with them: the rainbow (Genesis 9:12-13) and the Sabbath (Exodus 31:16-17) are two examples. Circumcision is another example. In case you are wondering, this covenant was a covenant with Abraham, and was fulfilled in Christ and is no longer required for followers of Jesus (1 Corinthians 7:19).</p>
        <p>Genesis 18: This chapter sets up the well-known story of the destruction of Sodom and Gomorrah.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan9">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?9</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 10</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.19.NIV">Genesis 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.20.NIV">Genesis 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.8.NIV">Psalm 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.1-6.NIV">Proverbs 3:1-6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.8.NIV">Matthew 8</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 20: Sarah's abduction by the king of Gerar threatens to undermine God's promise that she will bear Abraham a son. Verse 4 indicates that the king of Gerar hadn't touched her. That is an important insight in light of Isaac's coming birth and the Promise that it would be Abraham's child.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 3:1-6: Verses 5-6 are the most popular verses in the book of Proverbs, and it is clear to see why.</p>
        <p>Matthew 8: The story of the centurian is best understood when you remember he was the "enemy." He was a Roman soldier who was in charge of an entire company of soldiers. He was not a Jew. He was a Gentile. God had a special, chosen relationship with the Jewish people, but the Gospels begin to show there is a place for those who are not Jews.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan10">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?10</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 11</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q0BrP8bqj0c" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.21.NIV">Genesis 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.22.NIV">Genesis 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.7-9.NIV">Proverbs 3:7-8</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read and watch today:</p>
        <p>Video: The video above will give you an overview of the New Testament. You may want to come back to this on occasion to remind you of the flow of the New Testament. </p>
        <p>Genesis 21: This chapter gets us closer to the start of the nation of Israel. In this chapter, we read of Isaac being born. All of Abraham's descendents aren't part of Israel. It is through Isaac the nation will come into existence. Abraham's son, Isaac, will have a son named Jacob. Jacob's name will be changed to "Israel" and all of his descendents are the "nation of Israel." By the way, Muslims call themselves the descendents of Ishmael- Abraham's son by Hagar. They believe Ishmael was the chosen son of Abraham, not Isaac.</p>
        <p>Genesis 22: It is interesting to note that Abraham was taken to Moriah to sacrifice his son. Mt. Moriah is the place where the Temple ended up being built (see 2 Chronicles 3:1). We don't know that it was on top of Mt. Moriah that Abraham was taken, but it would make sense if he was taken there.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan11">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?11</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 12</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ALsluAKBZ-c" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.23.NIV">Genesis 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.24.NIV">Genesis 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.9-18.NIV">Proverbs 3:9-18</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read and watch today:</p>
        <p>Video: The video above will give you an overview of the Old Testament. You may want to come back to this on occasion to remind you of the flow of the Old Testament.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 3:9-10: Proverbs are not promises, but are principles for life that the authors of the book of Proverbs have seen to be true. We should not primarily take the words in Proverbs as promises of God, but wisdom from God. These two verses are verses that Christians have lived out for centuries. When you are generous with what God has given you, He often gives you more. It isn't why we are generous, but it sure is encouraging.</p>
        <p>Genesis 24: This lengthy chapter gives incredible detail of Rebekah becoming Isaac's wife. It shows how God directed Abraham's servant to her, but it also seems to intentionally show how she follows in Abraham's steps by leaving her family and country to settle in the Promised Land.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan12">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?12</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 13</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.25.NIV">Genesis 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.26.NIV">Genesis 26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.9.NIV">Psalm 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.11-12.NIV">Proverbs 3:11-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.9.NIV">Matthew 9</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 26: In this chapter you will see incidents happen to Isaac similarly to how they happened to Abraham, and you will see Isaac's actions closely parallel his father's. </p>
        <p>Psalm 9: The first two verses are great ones to memorize and pray to God. Sometimes knowing how to praise God in fresh ways can be a challenge. Verses like these can help you praise and thank God in meaningful ways, especially when memorized. </p>
        <p>Matthew 9: Verses 37-38 are instructions Jesus gave His disciples that we should still follow today. Truly, there are so many people who don't know the good news of Jesus and we should pray that God would send more and more people to share the Good News with them!</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan13">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?13</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 14</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.27.NIV">Genesis 27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.28.NIV">Genesis 28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.10.NIV">Psalm 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.13-15.NIV">Proverbs 3:13-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.10.NIV">Matthew 10</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Proverbs 3:13-15: This is one of the places where wisdom is personified - and referred to as "she."</p>
        <p>Matthew 10: Jesus' focus was on Israel with hints of grace toward Gentiles. This chapter also shows there is a cost to following Jesus. Following Jesus isn't to be a casual affair. Verses 38-39 are statements from Jesus reminding us that coming to faith in Jesus has implications for how we live. </p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan14">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?14</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 15</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.29.NIV">Genesis 29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.30.NIV">Genesis 30</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.11.NIV">Psalm 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.16-18.NIV">Proverbs 3:16-18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.11.NIV">Matthew 11</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 29-30: In these chapters we are introduced to Jacob's sons, who will become the 12 tribes of Israel (with some interesting twists).</p>
        <p>Proverbs 3:16-18: Proverbs makes great promises for those who learn and embrace Wisdom. This is the reason we choose to have you read slowly through the book of Proverbs. This one book alone can be life-changing. Be sure to be highlighting (if using the app) or underlining (if using a physical Bible) the verses that resonate with what God is doing in your heart.</p>
        <p>Matthew 11: After the difficult words from chapter 10, chapter 11 ends with a reminder that following Jesus is where we find true rest.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan15">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?15</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 16</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.31.NIV">Genesis 31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.32.NIV">Genesis 32</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.12.NIV">Psalm 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.19-20.NIV">Proverbs 3:19-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.12.NIV">Matthew 12</a></li>
        </ul> 
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 32: 20 years have passed since Jacob fled from Esau, and now he prepares to meet his brother again. Later in this chapter you will read of Jacob's name being changed to Israel, and why. This is the first mention of "Israel" in the Bible. Knowing it was a man's name before a nation's name may help you understand why the Israelites were often called, "The Children of Israel." They literally were the descendents of Israel (Jacob).</p>
        <p>Matthew 12: As you read, notice we aren't even halfway through the book of Matthew and the plotting begins for how to have Jesus crucified (v. 14). Notice that although Jesus came to die, it isn't time yet. He avoids the moments that would lead to His premature death (v. 15). The time for public confrontations would come later. This wasn't one of those times.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan16">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?16</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 17</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.33.NIV">Genesis 33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.34.NIV">Genesis 34</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.13.NIV">Psalm 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.21-26.NIV">Proverbs 3:21-26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.13.NIV">Matthew 13</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 34: This chapter is proof that the Bible is not rated PG or even PG-13. Remember the covenant to Abraham: Land, Seed, and Blessing. The book of Genesis is focused most on "Seed." Will God keep His promise and have His people survive? This chapter tells a story that threatens the future security of the family. A terrible crime happens, but the punishment chosen by two of Jacob's sons (the Children of Israel) doesn't fit the crime. Notice God is never mentioned in the story. These are the responsive actions of angry brothers, not the righteous response of judgment. Also notice that the Covenant of Circumcision was intended by God for a divine blessing and relationship, not for a deceptive way to lead to death and destruction. It is a fascinating and sad story.</p>
        <p>Psalm 13: This is a great Psalm that proves we can pour our hearts out to God and share how we truly feel. I think it is a model for us in our prayers. Share your suffering and questions (vv. 1-2). Tell God what you would like Him to do (vv. 3-4). But be sure to express your trust in Him even when things aren't going as you want them to (vv. 5-6).</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan17">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?17</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 18</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.35.NIV">Genesis 35</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.36.NIV">Genesis 36</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.27-32.NIV">Proverbs 3:27-32</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 35: This is a chapter showing the transfer from one generation to another (from Isaac to Jacob). In vv. 9-12, you see the Abrahamic Covenant reiterated to Jacob: land (v. 12), seed (v. 11), and blessing (v. 9).</p>
        <p>Proverbs 3:27-32: This is a reminder to us that followers of God should be good people and good neighbors: not so we can have a relationship with God, but because we do have relationship with Him.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan18">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?18</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 19</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.37.NIV">Genesis 37</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.38.NIV">Genesis 38</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.3.33-35.NIV">Proverbs 3:33-35</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 37: Notice the last chapter began with Isaac's family line, and now in chapter 37, we have Jacob's family line. The Abrahamic Promise has now officially passed to the next generation. This chapter begins the stories of Joseph. Remember, Genesis is focused on the "seed" part of the Abrahamic Covenant. It is constantly showing us the tension of the survival of God's chosen people. And the survival is going to happen through one of Jacob's sons, Joseph.</p> 
        <p>Genesis 38: If you thought the story in Genesis 34 was difficult to read, this one takes it to an entirely new level. This chapter is once again concerned about descendents (the "seed" promise Genesis focuses on). But it also focuses on the unrighteousness of Judah. Judah's sin provides a direct contrast to his brother Joseph's choices in chapter 39. But it is also a story of grace, as the line of Judah is the one through which Jesus will be born to save us from our sins.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan19">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?19</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 20</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GGCF3OPWN14" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.39.NIV">Genesis 39</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.40.NIV">Genesis 40</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.14.NIV">Psalm 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.4.1-6.NIV">Proverbs 4:1-6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.14.NIV">Matthew 14</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 39: This chapter and the next tell us two of the best known stories of Joseph. The story of Joseph and Potiphar's wife is often told and highlights Joseph for being a purity hero. However, the point of chapter 39 is easily missed. Joseph fleeing temptation is a valuable lesson in the chapter, but as you read, notice the repetition of the phrase, "the LORD was with Joseph." The chapter begins and ends with the phrase. The phrases are intentional "bookends" to put the story in context and let us know who the hero of the story is. It isn't Joseph. It is God's grace that is available to us in times of temptation.</p> 
        <p>Video: Be sure to watch the video from the link above. It will give you an understanding of what is coming in the rest of the book of Matthew.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan20">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?20</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 21</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.41.NIV">Genesis 41</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.42.NIV">Genesis 42</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.15.NIV">Psalm 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.4.7-10.NIV">Proverbs 4:7-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.15.NIV">Matthew 15</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 41-42: It is helpful to remember that the focus of Genesis (after Genesis 12) is God's promise of descendents to Abraham and the survival of God's people. These two chapters continue in that theme with how God worked behind the scenes to protect the future of His people. Chapter 42 expresses Jacob's fear of sending all of his children to Egypt, especially his favored son, Benjamin. But through the entire story, you can see God using the circumstances to keep His promises to Abraham.</p> 
        <p>Matthew 15: Jesus again feeds a large crowd, but this time it is a crowd of Gentiles. This would be surprising to Jewish people - since it is the Jews who are God's people. This was a demonstration by Jesus that the Good News was for Gentiles too.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan21">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?21</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 22</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.43.NIV">Genesis 43</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.44.NIV">Genesis 44</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.16.NIV">Psalm 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.4.11-13.NIV">Proverbs 4:11-13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.16.NIV">Matthew 16</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 16: This is another great Psalm expressing trust while David is clearly under strain and wondering about the future. This is a great Psalm to read, study and learn when life is difficult but you long to keep trusting God.</p>
        <p>Matthew 16: In the chapter, Jesus makes clear to His disciples that He will die. In their sadness and confusion, Jesus's disciples and especially Peter refuse to accept Jesus' prediction. Jesus confronted Peter directly, and in it He confronts us all with our understanding of what it means to follow Him.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan22">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?22</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 23</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.45.NIV">Genesis 45</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.46.NIV">Genesis 46</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.17.NIV">Psalm 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.4.14-19.NIV">Proverbs 4:14-19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.17.NIV">Matthew 17</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 46: This chapter begins to fulfill the promise God made to Abraham about leaving the Promised Land (for 400 years). It also is another list of people. Although it can be easy to lose interest in this section, remember the book of Genesis is consumed with answering the question, "will God keep his promise to Abraham about descendents?". Now we are told there are only 70 people that make up this "nation"- and they are headed to Egypt.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan23">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?23</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f9334tybhgfv985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 24</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.47.NIV">Genesis 47</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.48.NIV">Genesis 48</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.18.1-15">Psalm 18:1-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.4.20-27.NIV">Proverbs 4:20-27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.18.NIV">Matthew 18</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 48: There is an emphasis on the blessing given to Ephraim and Manasseh. Those become two of the tribes of Israel. So are there now 13 tribes of Israel? At times, the tribes of Ephraim and Manasseh are treated as "half-tribes" that belong together. But once Exodus begins, the focus will commonly move from the descendents promise to the land promise based on the Abrahamic Covenant. As priests, the tribe of Levi is not given land because of their priestly duties. Instead the land is divided between 12 tribes, including both Ephraim and Manasseh (Joseph's children) as individual tribes.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan24">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?24</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f56yhgf53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>January 25</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.49.NIV">Genesis 49</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/GEN.50.NIV">Genesis 50</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.5.1-6.NIV">Proverbs 5:1-6</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Genesis 49: Jacob is about to die and blesses each of his sons, indicating their past actions and something about the future for their descendents. Jacob uses poetic imagery and languages which can make them difficult to interpret clearly.</p>
        <p>Genesis 50: Verse 20 is an important verse on how a person's actions with evil intent can be used by God in spite of sinful intentions. It is a verse of great hope. Verse 21 continues the theme of descendents. Verse 24 focuses on the second promise of the Abrahamic Covenant, land.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 5: This chapter vividly warns against sexual immorality.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan25">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?25</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f3fer53985f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 26</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/0uf-PgW7rqE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.1.NIV">Exodus 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.1.NIV">Exodus 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.5.7-14.NIV">Proverbs 5:7-14</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Exodus 1: Moses (the writer of Exodus) puts the question of descendents to rest in verses 6-7 when we are told that "the land was filled with" Israelites. The rest of the book will focus on the second Abrahamic promise of the Land. And the rest of the book is about them leaving Egypt, heading toward the Promised Land, and giving them the Law - how God and His people will relate to each other.</p>
        <p>Exodus 2: This chapter contains two stories of God sparing the life of Moses - the main character of the next few books of the Bible. The chapter ends with God "remembering" His covenant with Abraham, Isaac, and with Jacob. As was mentioned before, the Hebrew word "remember" means "to bring to mind."</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan26">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?26</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f93vfcaf</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 27</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.3.NIV">Exodus 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.4.NIV">Exodus 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.18.16-24.NIV">Psalm 18:16-24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.5.15-21.NIV">Proverbs 5:15-21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.19.NIV">Matthew 19</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Exodus 3: This is a chapter telling the story of the call of Moses. At the burning bush, God reveals Himself, His promises, and His purpose to Moses.</p>
        <p>Exodus 4: God then demonstrates His power both through and for Moses.</p>
        <p>Matthew 19: The chapter begins and ends with some hard sayings of Jesus, but between them is the well-known story of God's care for children.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan27">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?27</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f93334gtyb85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 28</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.5.NIV">Exodus 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.6.NIV">Exodus 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.18.25-29.NIV">Psalm 18:25-29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.5.22-23.NIV">Proverbs 5:22-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.20.NIV">Matthew 20</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Exodus 5-6: In these chapters the confrontations between Moses and Pharaoh begin, and God promises Moses that He will deliver His people. Notice the repetition of the phrase, "I am the LORD." When you see "LORD" with all capital letters, it is the Hebrew name for God, Yahweh. That name is used in contexts of God being a covenant-keeping God. He is emphasizing that He is able to keep His covenant, and He will.</p>
        <p>Matthew 20: In this chapter, Jesus predicts His death for the third time. That is immediately followed by a bold request from the mother of two of Jesus' disciples.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan28">
      ]]> 
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?28</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f93erfcs5f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 29</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.7.NIV">Exodus 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.8.NIV">Exodus 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.18.30-36.NIV">Psalm 18:30-36</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.6.1-5.NIV">Proverbs 6:1-5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.21.NIV">Matthew 21</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Exodus 7-8: The first four of ten plagues come to Egypt. After two of them, Pharaoh promises to let the people go, but after the second and fourth plague, his heart is hardened and he changes his mind.</p>
        <p>Matthew 21: This chapter begins the last week before the death and resurrection of Jesus. Jesus' interactions with the religious leaders become more intense. At the time there were many in Jerusalem preparing for the Passover celebration. The confrontations Jesus has with the religious leaders were very public and well-witnessed.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan29">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?29</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933frevd85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 30</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.9.NIV">Exodus 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.10.NIV">Exodus 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.18.37-50.NIV">Psalm 18:37-50</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.6.6-11.NIV">Proverbs 6:6-11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.22.NIV">Matthew 22</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Exodus 9-10: Plagues five through nine occur in these chapters. With three of them, Pharaoh promises to let the people go, but with each one, Pharaoh's heart was hardened and he refused. This sets up the final showdown in chapters 11-12.</p>
        <p>Matthew 22: The confrontations intensify between Jesus and the religious leaders. They are doing all they can to trap Him in His words so they can have a reason to discredit Him and arrest Him.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan30">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?30</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933qwrefv85f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>January 31</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.11.NIV">Exodus 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/EXO.12.NIV">Exodus 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.19.NIV">Psalm 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.6.12-15.NIV">Proverbs 6:12-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/MAT.23.NIV">Matthew 23</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>A note on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Exodus 12: This becomes the most important moment in Jewish history in the Old Testament and becomes an annual celebration of God's people. It is called The Passover and God commands they remember this day every year.</p>
        <p>Psalm 19: This Psalm is in two parts - praising God for creation and for His Word. Theologically, creation is called "General Revelation" because it is available to everyone and gives a general understanding of who God is. Special Revelation is given by God to reveal His way of salvation. General Revelation would include creation and the human conscience. Special Revelation includes Jesus Christ and the Bible.</p>
        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jan31">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?31</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">6bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933cdds</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 16:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
