<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Daily Reading</title>
  <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
  <link>https://newheights.org</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

  <!-- <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/.NIV"></a></li> -->
  <!-- <iframe src="https://youtu.be/JqOqJlFF_eU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe> -->

  <item>
    <title>May 1</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.5.NIV">1 Samuel 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.6.NIV">1 Samuel 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.63.NIV">Psalm 63</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.15-16.NIV">Proverbs 14:15-16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.20.NIV">John 20</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 5-6: As you read about the Ark of the Covenant, try not to think of it as only a relic or a special piece of furniture. At the time, it was the place where God was to meet with the high priest. Instead, the people of Israel used it like an idol or good luck charm and took it with them into battles. And in these chapters, God made sure the ark did not stay with the Philistines.</p>
        <p>John 20: The story of Mary realizing who Jesus is one of my (Natalie's) favorite stories. I love how it is when Jesus calls her by name that it wakes Mary up to the reality that Jesus is alive and standing right in front of her. The suffering and death she witnessed two days ago is gone because Jesus is alive and has overcome all death and sin. The tenderness in their relationship - where it only takes Him saying her name for her to understand - is another example to me of Jesus' care and personal love for each person He encountered.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May1">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?120</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 2</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.7.NIV">1 Samuel 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.8.NIV">1 Samuel 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.17-19.NIV">Proverbs 14:17-19</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 8: The Israelites' desire for a king was founded in their desire to want to look like the other nations surrounding them. It was a lack of faith in God to deliver them from their enemies. They wanted to look to a king for protection, rather than trust in a God they could not see. It is a good moment for us to pause and consider- Where do we lack faith in God? Where do we want to look like unbelievers because it seems easier than trusting God?</p>
        <p>Proverbs 14: The theme of caring and being kind to the needy is carried throughout the entire Bible. God is serious about how we treat one another, especially those who are poor or needy.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May2">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?121</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 3</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.9.NIV">1 Samuel 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.10.NIV">1 Samuel 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.20-21.NIV">Proverbs 14:20-21</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 9: Saul's response of being from the tribe of Benjamin is referring to the fact that Benjamin was a very small tribe, and had shrunk even smaller during the time of the judges. God choosing Saul is yet another demonstration - similar to Gideon - that God can do whatever He wants with anyone, no matter how small or lowly the circumstances surrounding the person may be.</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 10: Chapters 9 and 10 are bittersweet because we see God's hand in choosing Saul, yet in the midst of the excitement is Samuel's warning in verse 19, "But you have now rejected your God, who saves you out of all your calamities and distresses." The people's celebration and shouting of, "Long live the king!" is their acceptance of a new king and their rejection of God's leadership.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May3">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?122</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 4</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.11.NIV">1 Samuel 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.12.NIV">1 Samuel 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.64.NIV">Psalm 64</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.22-24.NIV">Proverbs 14:22-24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/JHN.21.NIV">John 21<a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        1 Samuel 12: In the end of Samuel's speech, the people finally see their great sin of desiring a king. Samuel's response to tell the people to turn to God and serve Him wholeheartedly is a good reminder for us. Even after we sin, we can always turn back to God and keep serving Him. He is gracious to forgive us and remind us that He is "pleased to make us His own." (v. 22)</p>
        <p>John 21: All four gospel accounts record Peter's denial of Jesus, but only John tells us of the restoration of Peter following Jesus' resurrection. As we move into the book of Acts, Peter will be a prominent figure in the life of the church, fulfilling Jesus' command to "feed my sheep." Jesus predicts Peter's death, alluding to painful suffering. Traditionally, it is believed that Peter was martyred by being crucified upside down because he did not consider himself worthy to suffer the same crucifixion as Jesus.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May4">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?123</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 5</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/CGbNw855ksw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.13.NIV">1Samuel 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.14.NIV">1Samuel 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.65.NIV">Psalm 65</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.25.NIV">Proverbs 14:25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.1.NIV">Acts 1</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 13: As quickly as we read of Saul coming to power, we learn that he will lose his kingdom. His decision to not wait for Samuel was blatant rebellion towards God. Samuel's charge earlier in chapter 12:14-15 says the people and the king need to follow the LORD, and we see Saul disregard God's leadership and take it upon himself to offer the burnt offering, which was the job of Samuel. Throughout the time of kings in Israel and Judah, we will see many of them struggle to listen to the voice of God through His prophets. Saul's punishment is a warning of kings going their own way and disregarding God's plan.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May5">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?124</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 6</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.15.NIV">1 Samuel 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.16.NIV">1 Samuel 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.66.1-12.NIV">Psalm 66:1-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.26-27.NIV">Proverbs 14:26-27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.2.NIV">Acts 2</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 15-16: Saul's demise begins as the Lord removes Himself from Saul. Samuel will no longer be bringing to him the word of the Lord, and in 15:14 we learn that the Spirit of the LORD has left Saul. Now the only interaction between God and Saul happens through David as he plays his harp.</p>
        <p>Psalm 66:11-12 - Nothing in our lives happens outside of God's hand. He can use the hard things in our lives to accomplish His purpose and bring us to a place of abundance.</p>
        <p>Acts 2: See the great empowerment brought about by the Holy Spirit in Peter. Nothing Peter has said in the past compares to this magnificent gospel presentation.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May6">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?125</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 7</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.17.NIV">1 Samuel 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.18.NIV">1 Samuel 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.66.13-20.NIV">Psalm 66:13-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.28-29.NIV">Proverbs 14:28-29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.3.NIV">Acts 3</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 17: Saul and the Israelites' fear shows their lack of faith in God and His ability to deliver them from their enemies. In contrast, David's faith is highlighted as he acts on his conviction that God will deliver him from Goliath and the Philistine army.</p>
        <p>Acts 3: After the healing of the man, people are amazed and full of wonder. Peter uses this moment to again present the gospel, calling the people to repent and turn to God.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May7">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?126</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 8</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
	<p><b>We want your feedback! <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSciZnXIraloSs3Kf-KvcyqVf0AyrdNQKUYLvQnQ2ZYIBKaDAA/viewform?usp=sf_link">Take this short survey</a> about our Daily Reading resources.</b> </p>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.19.NIV">1 Samuel 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.20.NIV">1 Samuel 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.67.NIV">Psalm 67</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.30-31.NIV">Proverbs 14:30-31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.4.NIV">Acts 4</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 19: God continues to frustrate Saul's plans to kill David in several ways - his own children turn on him and help David, and then the Spirit of God moves in Saul's heart causing him to prophesy instead of killing David.</p>
        <p>Psalm 67: The first verse echoes the priestly benediction given in Number 24. Notice how this prayer is not just for the people of Israel, but also a prayer for all nations to praise God and be blessed by Him.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 14:31: Jesus will extend this message in His teaching, by saying that however we treat the least of these He considers to be how we treat Him (Matthew 25).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May8">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?127</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 9</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.21.NIV">1 Samuel 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.22.NIV">1 Samuel 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.32-33.NIV">Proverbs 14:32-33</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 21: Jesus refers to this incident of David and his men eating the "bread of the Presence" which was meant only for the priests. Jesus explains in Mark 2 that it is lawful to do good and save life rather than be legalistic about the ceremonial laws.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 14:32 Even when faced with death, the righteous have a refuge because their hope and eternal home is in God.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May9">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?128</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 10</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.23.NIV">1 Samuel 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.24.NIV">1 Samuel 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.14.34-35.NIV">Proverbs 14:34-35</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 23-24: David's character is displayed over these chapters as we see him choose to care for the people of Israel, even while Saul pursues him to kill him. Saul has moments of remorse and clarity, but they are soon clouded by his jealousy and desperate attempts to maintain his kingship by eliminating the threat of David.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May10">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?129</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 11</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.25.NIV">1 Samuel 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.26.NIV">1 Samuel 26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.68.1-10.NIV">Psalm 68:1-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.1-3.NIV">Proverbs 15:1-3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.5.NIV">Acts 5</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Acts 5: Ananias and Sapphira enter as a contrast to Barnabas's generosity, noted in Acts 4:46-37. Their judgement by the Holy Spirit is similar to the judgment shown at the beginning of new eras for the people of God: Aaron's sons are struck down in Leviticus 10 (the beginning of the priestly order), Achan is killed for his sin in Joshua 7 (the beginning of moving into the promised land), Uzzah is killed in 2 Samuel 6 (the beginning of David's reign). These warnings show the serious way God views sin. Ananias and Sapphira's sin is not that they didn't give all of the money to the apostles, but that they lied about in hopes of gaining praise and admiration.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May11">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?130</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 12</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.27.NIV">1 Samuel 27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.28.NIV">1 Samuel 28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.68.11-23.NIV">Psalm 68:11-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.4.NIV">Proverbs 15:4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.6.NIV">Acts 6</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 28: There are several theories for the witchcraft in this story, but regardless of how Samuel appeared, the truth is proclaimed to Saul. His sin has led to his demise, and he will not survive against the Philistines.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 15:4: The author demonstrates the power that is held within our words. The imagery of "tree of life" brings to mind the tree in the garden of Eden. A tree with such great power, that God did not allow Adam and Eve to eat from it after they had sinned (Genesis 3).</p>
        <p>Acts 6: Biblical scholars think there might have been a good amount of time between chapters 5 and 6. The church is continuing to grow, bringing up some problems. This shows the first account of the Twelve apostles giving leadership of the church to other people.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May12">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?131</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 13</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.29.NIV">1 Samuel 29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.30.NIV">1 Samuel 30</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.68.24-35.NIV">Psalm 68:24-35</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.5-7.NIV">Proverbs 15:5-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.7.NIV">Acts 7</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Proverbs 15:5: Discipline is never pleasant, but it is important to accept it so we can become who God is creating us to be.</p>
        <p>Acts 7: Stephen ends his speech with a charge against the Sanhedrin - resulting in their irate stoning of him. The text notes in verse 58 that there was a young man there named Saul. Some believe that Saul had authority over the people there and was responsible for the stoning of Stephen. This is the first introduction to Saul, and his story will continue in chapter 9.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May13">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?132</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 14</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1SA.31.NIV">1 Samuel 31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.69.1-12.NIV">Psalm 69:1-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.8-10.NIV">Proverbs 15:8-10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.8.NIV">Acts 8</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Samuel 31: The tragedy of Saul's life is massive. The death of his sons, including David's beloved friend Jonathan, are sad reminders that sin often has collateral damage.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 15:8: God is not interested in the sacrifices from people who are unwilling to repent and seek His forgiveness. It is a good reminder that God is not pleased in the "good things" we do for Him if it is not done with a pure heart.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May14">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?133</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 15</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/YvoWDXNDJgs" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.1.NIV">2 Samuel 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.2.NIV">2 Samuel 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.69.13-29.NIV">Psalm 69:13-29</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.11.NIV">Proverbs 15:11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.9.NIV">Acts 9</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 1: Originally just one book, 2nd Samuel picks up right where 1st Samuel ended, with Saul dying and David hearing about it. Despite being anointed king over Judah, David still has many battles ahead before he is king over all Israel. The reason the books of Samuel, Kings, and Chronicles are in two parts is simply because none could fit on one scroll. And that has led to us calling them 1 & 2 Samuel, 1 & 2 Kings, and 1 & 2 Chronicles.</p>
        <p>Acts 9: Jesus saying to Saul, "why do you persecute me?" shows just how closely Jesus identifies with the Church. He takes their persecution personally. In this instance, He chooses to step in and protect His Church, while also turning its greatest enemy into its greatest missionary. Saul's experience with Jesus on the Damascus road permanently changes him and he immediately begins preaching the gospel.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May15">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?134</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 16</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.3.NIV">2 Samuel 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.4.NIV">2 Samuel 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.12-14.NIV">Proverbs 15:12-14</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 3-4: The story of Joab and his brother Abishai murdering Abner will be a narrative that continues later in time. Their actions were sinful because it was motivated by revenge and done during a time of peace making. David does not punish Joab, but the rest of Joab's story is played out with King Solomon in 1 Kings 2.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May16">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?135</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>1 Kings

  <item>
    <title>May 17</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.5.NIV">2 Samuel 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.6.NIV">2 Samuel 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.15-17.NIV">Proverbs 15:15-17</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 5: One of David's greatest achievements was capturing and establishing his rule in Jerusalem. It was naturally situated on top of a hill, with three valleys surrounding it. Because of this, it was hard for enemies to attack because they were forced to attack while going uphill.</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 6: The story of Uzzah is a time of God's justice and holiness. His people must listen and obey His laws wholeheartedly. David's response of anger and fear show his wrestling with this concept. An initial reading of this story may feel harsh, but the Old Testament law was clear. They were to carry the ark using poles. Instead, the built a new cart for the ark. The motive may have been good, but obedience matters.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 15:16-17: These verses are good reminders to pause and think if we would rather settle for earthly treasures/valuables over godliness.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May17">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?136</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 18</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.7.NIV">2 Samuel 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.8.NIV">2 Samuel 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.69.30-36.NIV">Psalm 69:30-36</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.18-19.NIV">Proverbs 15:18-19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.10.NIV">Acts 10</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 7-8: A time of great favor and blessing on David. This promise from God (later called a covenant in 2 Samuel 23:5) is a powerful moment for David, but will ultimately be fulfilled through Jesus Christ, through Whom God will "establish the throne of his kingdom forever." (7:13)</p>
        <p>Acts 10: Peter understood that God was not just talking to him about clean and unclean food, but was instead breaking down the barrier between Jews and Gentiles. As the leader of the Church, Peter was being called to accept and spread the good news to all people.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May18">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?137</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 19</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.9.NIV">2 Samuel.9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.10.NIV">2 Samuel.10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.70.NIV">Psalm 70</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.20-21.NIV">Proverbs 15:20-21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.11.NIV">Acts 11</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 9: David keeps his promise to be true to Jonathan, established in 1 Samuel 20. His kindness towards Mephibosheth not only keeps that promise, but peacefully ends all possible threats from Saul's lineage to David's kingship.</p>
        <p>Psalm 70: Psalms and prayers come in all shapes and sizes, and this one shows a quick and intense plea for help. Sometimes all we can do is ask God for help and trust that He will not delay. (70:5).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May19">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?138</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 20</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.11.NIV">2 Samuel 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.12.NIV">2 Samuel 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.71.1-13.NIV">Psalm 71:1-13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.22-23.NIV">Proverbs 15:22-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.12.NIV">Acts 12</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 11-12: David's sin in this chapter shifts his story from that of a conquering king who seems to be untouchable and undefeatable, to a king who struggles to live righteously. Up until this point, David has been shown himself to be a mighty warrior, honorable in his dealings with people, and faithful to keep God's commands. There have been moments of weakness in his story (perhaps seen in not dealing with Joab), but his sin with Bathsheba and murderous plot against Uriah is where he falls. From this point, the strife within his family will increase and be a great source of pain for David. To read his Psalm of repentance following Nathan's rebuke, see Psalm 51.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May20">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?139</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 21</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/Z-17KxpjL0Q" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.13.NIV">2 Samuel 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.14.NIV">2 Samuel 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.71.14-18.NIV">Psalm 71:14-18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.24-26.NIV">Proverbs 15:24-26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.13.NIV">Acts 13</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 13-14: The disturbing story of Amnon assaulting Tamar leads only to more violence and strife within David's family.</p>
        <p>Psalm 71:17: This is one of my (Natalie's) favorite verses. I love the thought of spending my life sharing about the marvelous works God has done.</p>
        <p>Acts 13: Here we see Saul start to be called Paul. Most likely the reason for this is that Paul will be preaching to a non-Jewish audience. Saul is a Hebrew/Jewish name, and Paul is a Roman name. It was not uncommon during that time to be given a new name- earlier we read in Acts 4 that Barnabas was a name given to him by the apostles, his name before that was Joseph.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May21">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?140</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 22</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.15.NIV">2 Samuel 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.16.NIV">2 Samuel 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.71.19-24.NIV">Psalm 71:19-24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.27-28.NIV">Proverbs 15:27-28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.14.NIV">Acts 14</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 15-16: Ahithophel was one of David's advisors and also the grandfather of Bathsheba. His betrayal in joining Absalom at this time may be revenge towards David for the way he treated Uriah and Bathsheba earlier. His advice to Absalom in the end of 2 Samuel 16 not only fulfills Nathan's prophecy from 2 Samuel 12, but it signifies a declaration of breaking off relationship between Absalom and David.</p>
        <p>Acts 14: Not only is Paul rising up after being stoned most likely miraculous, this may have been a moment witnessed by Timothy, who was from Lystra. Paul would later write at least two letters to Timothy.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May22">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?141</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 23</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.17.NIV"> 2 Samuel 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.18.NIV"> 2 Samuel 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.29-30.NIV">Proverbs 15:29-30</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 18: Joab's plans did not always align with King David's, and the death of Absalom despite David's plea to save him is an example of Joab's somewhat indifference to the king's wishes at times. The over-the-top killing of Absalom and then the pile of rocks under which he was buried was intended to make a mockery of the pillar Absalom had created for himself.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May23">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?142</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 24</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.19.NIV">2 Samuel 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.20.NIV">2 Samuel 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.31-32.NIV">Proverbs 15:31-32</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 19: David listens to Joab's rebuke, and goes to greet his soldiers instead of continuing to mourn Absalom's death. This chapter ties up some of the stories from earlier regarding Mephibosheth, Shimei, and Barzillai.</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 20: Joab commits murder against Amasa in order to gain control of the entire military. Sheba's rebellion against David is the final threat that is defeated in the time of David's leadership.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May24">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?143</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 25</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.21.NIV">2 Samuel 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.22.NIV">2 Samuel 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.72.1-7.NIV">Psalm 72:1-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.15.33.NIV">Proverbs 15:33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.15.NIV">Acts 15</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 21-22: These last four chapters of 2 Samuel are the appendix to 1&2 Samuel. The following stories are not in chronological order, but tell different stories from the reign of David. </p>
        <p>2 Samuel 22: This song from David is also recorded in Psalm 18.</p>
        <p>Acts 15: An important moment in the Church where the leaders decide how to assimilate their faith with the Gentiles. The four things they decide to keep instead of requiring circumcision are asking Gentiles to abstain from food polluted by idols, sexual immorality, meat from strangled animals, and from blood. These things were selected for their relation to Mosaic laws and were all behaviors practiced by many Gentiles that were incredibly repulsive to Jewish believers.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May25">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?144</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 26</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.23.NIV">2 Samuel 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2SA.24.NIV">2 Samuel 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.72.8-20.NIV">Psalm 72:8-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.1-3.NIV">Proverbs 16:1-3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.16.NIV">Acts 16</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Samuel 24: This account is also told in 1 Chronicles 21, where it says that Satan told David to take a census. Whether it was incited by Satan or God, all of it is under God's sovereign rule. Historians believe that this event happened somewhere after the time of the rebellions of Absalom and Sheba, and may be a punishment towards the people who rejected David as king.</p>
        <p>Acts 16: Paul goes on several missionary trips throughout the book of Acts. Having a good map of his different paths is helpful when reading about the many different cities he visits. Most study Bibles will include maps, but simply searching for "Paul's missionary journeys" on the internet will be beneficial for visualizing his routes.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May26">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?145</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 27</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/bVFW3wbi9pk" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.1.NIV">1 Kings 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.2.NIV">1 Kings 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.73.1-12.NIV">Psalm 73:1-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.4-5.NIV">Proverbs 16:4-5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.17.NIV">Acts 17</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 1: There are pieces from several accounts that need to be put together, but it is clear that God chooses Solomon to be the next king of Israel. In 1 Chronicles 22:9-10, David refers back to a time when God said that Solomon would be the next king. Adonijah has not been selected by God to rule, and is obvious in the way that Adonijah deceitfully goes about usurping the throne from his father. David swore a vow to Bathsheba that her son Solomon would be king, so she goes to David to remind him of that vow.</p>
        <p>Acts 17: Paul was very aware of his audience. When he presents the Gospel to Jewish followers of God, he focuses on Jesus' resurrection and Him being the Promised Messiah. But here in Athens, he must take a very different approach. They weren't followers of God at all. His approached changed significantly. In his message at Athens, he quotes several greek poets (Aratus and Cleanthes), taking their words and then applying the reality of the Gospel.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May27">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?146</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 28</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.3.NIV">1 Kings 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.4.NIV">1 Kings 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.73.13-22.NIV">Psalm 73:13-22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.6-7.NIV">Proverbs 16:6-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.18.NIV">Acts 18</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 3: In verse 2 the author mentions that the people were making sacrifices at the high places because there was not yet a temple. Many of these high places were left over from previous inhabitants of the land, and became places where the people were led into temptation to offer sacrifices to other gods.</p>
        <p>Acts 18: Paul has several visions of Jesus following the time of his conversion. This instance in verse 9 provided clear direction for staying in Corinth. When he goes to leave, Paul has his hair taken off. This is most likely because he had taken a Nazarite vow (Number 6 gives an explanation), and at the end of the vow the person cuts off their hair.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May28">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?147</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 29</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.5.NIV">1 Kings 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.6.NIV">1 Kings 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.73.23-28.NIV">Psalm 73:23-28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.8-9.NIV">Proverbs 16:8-9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.19.NIV">Acts 19</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 5: Here we learn that Solomon will be the one to build the temple, not David. In 1 Chronicles 22 David says that God would not allow for him to build the temple because of all of the bloodshed in wars he was responsible for having done. God promised that Solomon's reign would be peaceful, thus providing the space for Solomon to build a temple. David was very involved in the planning of the temple, and gave his blessing and plans to Solomon before he passed away.</p>
        <p>Psalm 73: The Psalm ends in a powerful declaration of God being more important and worthy than anything else in our lives. These beautiful words remind us of all that we have in God.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May29">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?148</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 30</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.7.NIV">1 Kings 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.8.NIV">1 Kings 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.10-11.NIV">Proverbs 16:10-11</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 7: The beginning of chapter 7 points out that the construction of Solomon's palace took almost twice as long as the construction of the temple. </p>
        <p>1 Kings 8: Similar to when God's presence filled the tabernacle at Mt. Sinai, He descended into the temple in a very visible way for the people to witness. And though he chose to dwell in the temple at this time, in his prayer Solomon makes it clear that God cannot be contained by any physical or earthly thing (v. 27). God will act however He best sees fit, and Solomon recognizes that.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May30">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?149</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>May 31</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.9.NIV">1 Kings 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.10.NIV">1 Kings 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.12-13.NIV">Proverbs 16:12-13</a></li>
        </ul>

        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 9: The LORD appeared to Solomon and reminded him of the covenant that He had made with David. This is especially important because Solomon is entering into a time of great wealth and prospering, and it is key that he is obedient to the Lord and not relying on his own wisdom or power or wealth. </p>
        <p>1 Kings 10: Jesus referenced the Queen of Sheba as someone who recognized that Solomon's wisdom came from the God he served. Jesus chided the listeners because they were unable to recognize that "one greater than Solomon" stood before them (Matthew 12:42).</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?May31">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?150</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
