<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
  <title>Daily Reading</title>
  <description>New Heights Daily Reading Plan</description>
  <link>https://newheights.org</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2021 00:01:10 +0000 </lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2021 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>

  <!-- <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/.NIV"></a></li> -->
  <!-- <iframe src="https://youtu.be/JqOqJlFF_eU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe> -->

  <item>
    <title>June 1</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.11.NIV">1 Kings 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.12.NIV">1 Kings 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.74.1-11.NIV">Psalm 74:1-11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.14-15.NIV">Proverbs 16:14-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.20.NIV">Acts 20</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 11-12: The end of Solomon’s life is very tragic. 700 wives sound bad today, and it was bad 3000 years ago. What this demonstrates is that Solomon ends up violating all the commands God gives for a king (read Deut. 17:14-20). This shows his divided heart and begins the nation's descent into captivity.</p>
        <p>Acts 20: In this chapter, the craziest event that happens is that Paul raises Eutychus from the dead. How can a normal guy raise someone from the dead? Well… Paul didn’t raise Eutychus from the dead, Jesus did! This was a validation that Jesus was using Paul. This is an important distinction. Paul was an Apostle sent by Jesus to further Jesus' ministry.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun1">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?151</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 2</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.13.NIV">1 Kings 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.14.NIV">1 Kings 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.74.12-23.NIV">Psalm 74:12-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.16-17.NIV">Proverbs 16:16-17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.21.NIV">Acts 21</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 13-14: In chapter 12, the nation of Israel splits in two (Israel in the north, Judah in the south). Much like the US civil war, it was a tragedy for God’s people to be divided. Jeroboam is the leader of Israel, and his insecurity led him to build two golden calves (twice as bad as the first golden calf story found in Exodus 32). He wants to be like David (the greatest king in Israel/Judah’s history) that he builds two places of worship, so the people will never have to go to Jerusalem, the actual place where God was to be worshipped. Ultimately it will lead to his death.</p>
        <p>Acts 21: The conflict in this chapter is Paul is removing barriers and hurdles, such as circumcision, from non-Jewish believers to believe in Christ. The challenge is the Jewish leaders are interpreting this as Paul renouncing the Jewish Law. This leads to the Jewish leaders trying to kill Paul.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun2">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?152</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 3</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.15.NIV">1 Kings 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.16.NIV">1 Kings 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.75.NIV">Psalm 75</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.18.NIV">Proverbs 16:18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.22.NIV">Acts 22</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 15-16: We pause the story of Israel’s kings to read about two kings of Judah, the southern Kingdom. One good, and one evil. The kings will be measured by how similar they were to King David. One thing to note as well. There will be no god-honoring kings in the northern kingdom of Israel. There will be a mix of good and bad kings in Judah where the promised Messiah will come from.</p>
        <p>Acts 22: Paul shares his faith story to the angry mob to proclaim the Good News. The Romans seeing the angry mob decided to flog Paul because inciting a riot was a crime against the Pax Romana (the peace of Rome). The Romans would make examples out of people to keep the peace. But, flogging a Roman citizen without a formal trial was illegal, therefore, Paul was supposed to get a Roman trial. Paul is a rare figure to be a former Pharisee and a Roman citizen. You can see why God would use him to reach people throughout the Roman empire. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun3">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?153</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 4</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.17.NIV">1 Kings 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.18.NIV">1 Kings 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.76.NIV">Psalm 76</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.19-20.NIV">Proverbs 16:19-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.23.NIV">Acts 23</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 17-18: We're introduced to the Prophet Elijah’s story. He's one of the most important prophets in all the Old Testament. His name means, “The LORD is God”. Honoring his namesake, he speaks against the idolatry of the people of Israel. Israelites are worshipping Baal and Asherah, idols that were believed to control rain and the weather. In an agricultural society, these are immensely important. Elijah calls a drought to demonstrate it’s the LORD who controls all things... not the idols. This culminates with a demonstration against the prophets of Baal. </p>
        <p>Acts 23: Notice the similarities between Jesus’ trial and Paul’s. Both were questioned by the Jewish Sanhedrin to Roman governors. Both are struck in the face during their trials, and both had the Jewish leaders plotting to kill them. This shows Paul is continuing the work of Jesus. His life is transformed by Jesus to look like Jesus in the world.  </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun4">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?154</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 5</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.19.NIV">1 Kings 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.20.NIV">1 Kings 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.77.1-12.NIV">Psalm 77:1-12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.21-23.NIV">Proverbs 16:21-23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.24.NIV">Acts 24</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 19-20: Elijah’s miraculous demonstration changed nothing for the queen of Israel; she still threatens to kill Elijah. He flees to Beersheba (the southern tip of the promised land) which was 120 miles away! He is terrified; similar to you or me. Yet, God shows him that God works not just through huge events but through the gentle whispers of life. </p>
        <p>Psalm 77:1-12: Whenever you read Selah, take a moment to pause. This is what that word is there for. It’s a time to pause and ponder what you just read. This is an intentional device to get us to reflect on the love of God in our live. </p>
        <p>Acts 24: Paul is kept in prison for two years by the Roman governors. Governor Felix dismisses the charges against Paul, but still holds him in jail with no timetable to get out. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun5">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?155</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 6</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.21.NIV">1 Kings 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1KI.22.NIV">1 Kings 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.24.NIV">Proverbs 16:24</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Kings 21-22: King Ahab and Queen Jezebel rob a man of his vineyard. We view it negatively today, but that doesn't do this story justice. What they do is atrocious then. First, to an Israelite, the land was a tangible representation of God’s promises to them and their family. Land was held in high regard, to simply steal land belonging to another family was a huge violation (See Leviticus 25:23-29). Second, they falsely accused him of a crime with two false witnesses, and then they killed him. Ahab and Jezebel do pay in the end. This all shows the corruption of the northern kingdom.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 16:24: Honey in the ancient near east was sweet to eat but also it was used commonly for medicinal purposes. The metaphor is applied to how we speak to one another, we can bring joy to another’s lives and healing as well. This proverb highlights the positive power of our words.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun6">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?156</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 7</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.1.NIV">2 Kings 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.2.NIV">2 Kings 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.25.NIV">Proverbs 16:25</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 1-2: After Ahab’s death, his son Ahaziah rules in Israel, and he is just as evil. He is severely injured, and seeks guidance from Baal-zebub (literally means, “the Lord of the flies”). This was a Philistine idol, and Ahaziah turns to the idol of flies rather than turning back to God. Subsequently, Elijah’s story is finished, he is taken up to heaven without dying. This validates his prophetic voice, and also gives validation to Elisha as the next prophet of Israel. Also, what’s the deal with the bears attacking the boys? Well in the ancient world, young people were supposed to deeply respect God’s prophets as they were speaking on God's behalf. This is meant to be another story demonstrating the degradation of Israel that even the young are abandoning and rebelling against God.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 16:25: This proverb highlights how people can be stuck in a paradigm that leads to destruction. It is why it is important to seek the wisdom the Proverbs have been advocating for.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun7">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?157</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 8</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.3.NIV">2 Kings 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.4.NIV">2 Kings 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.77.13-20.NIV">Psalm 77:13-20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.26-27.NIV">Proverbs 16:26-27</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.25.NIV">Acts 25</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 3-4: Notice how Elisha stories are very similar to Elisha’s from 1 Kings 17. This is meant to highlight Elisha as the prophet from God. Elisha means, “God saves”. His life will be like Elijah’s displaying God saving his people. </p>
        <p>Acts 25: Since Paul has been locked up in prison with no end in sight, he appeals to go to Rome to have a trial with Caesar. Roman citizens had the right to appeal before Caesar for their trial. Paul's in between a rock and a hard place; if his trial is in Jerusalem, Festus (the new governor) will kill him to please the Jewish leaders. If he goes to Rome, Nero Caesar could surmise that Paul is disturbing the peace and kill him there (Nero hated Christians). Paul takes his chance with Rome. Behind it all is God, who is spreading the Good News of Jesus through Paul all the way to the most powerful city on Earth at this time. </p>


        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun8">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?158</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 9</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.5.NIV">2 Kings 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.6.NIV">2 Kings 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.78.1-8.NIV">Psalm 78:1-8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.28-30.NIV">Proverbs 16:28-30</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.26.NIV">Acts 26</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 5-6: Naaman’s story is a powerful one that demonstrates that God is in control of the whole world, not just Israel. Why doesn't Elisha meet in person with Naaman? Why doesn't he take the gifts Naaman is offering? In the ancient near east, prophets were synonymous with healing and miracles. Elisha’s actions demonstrate that all the healing came from God, not from him; this is why Elisha does not accept the payment. It was God who healed Naaman, not Elisha.</p>
        <p>Acts 26: Due to Paul’s imprisonment, he is able to share the Gospel even with the Roman rulers. It’s a powerful example that God is using Paul’s suffering to reveal the Good News to the entire known world.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun9">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?159</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 10</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.7.NIV">2 Kings 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.8.NIV">2 Kings 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.78.9-16.NIV">Psalm 78:9-16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.16.31-33.NIV">Proverbs 16:31-33</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.27.NIV">Acts 27</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 7-8: If you remember Naaman’s story in chapter five, he was a leper who led the Syrians to Israel. Chapter 7 has 4 lepers who drive the Syrians out. The other ironic element of the story is that Naaman was a Gentile captain who believed God at the end of his story, but when God does something miraculous, the Israelite captain does not believe. 1 & 2 Kings are overflowing with irony and role reversals.</p>
        <p>Acts 27: Paul is set to sail to Rome for his trial. He sails around winter (verse 9 tells us it’s past "the fast" or Day of Atonement which is in the fall). The winter would be a terrible time to sail due to wind conditions being rough. The people would sail using the sun and stars for direction (which are not visible during storms). Therefore, the situation seems hopeless. But what seems terrible ends up being a great opportunity for Paul to leave an impact on these Roman sailors. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun10">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?160</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 11</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.9.NIV">2 Kings 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.10.NIV">2 Kings 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.78.17-31.NIV">Psalm 78:17-31</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.1.NIV">Proverbs 17:1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ACT.28.NIV">Acts 28</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 9-10: God appoints Jehu as king of Israel to fulfill the prophecy of the destruction of Ahab and his line (see 1 Kings 21:21-24). This seems harsh today... but in the ancient near east, when a monarchy was overthrown, the whole line was killed to avoid any opportunity for retaliation. Behind all this is the fact that God is patient, but He is also just. He will not tolerate evil. Ahab, and His family persecuted and killed God’s prophets, and even after seeing God work, they still would not repent.</p>
        <p>Acts 28: Paul spends the winter months shipwrecked on the island of Malta, but while he’s there he does not miss the opportunity to share the Good News with his actions. The conclusion of Acts shows the Gospel had already spread into Rome with “brothers”  already being there (Paul’s letter to the Romans was written before his arrival). God sovereignly placed Paul in Rome to have an effective ministry. Rome was the epicenter of the known world at this point and the perfect conclusion to Acts in which Jesus called the Apostles to be witnesses in Jerusalem, Judea, Samaria, and ultimately to the ends of the Earth. Paul in Rome encapsulates the process of the Gospel reaching the ends of the Earth.</p>


        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun11">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?161</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 12</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/ej_6dVdJSIU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.11.NIV">2 Kings 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.12.NIV">2 Kings 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.78.32-39.NIV">Psalm 78:32-39</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.2-3.NIV">Proverbs 17:2-3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.1.NIV">Romans 1</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 11-12: Athaliah, will now be queen in the southern kingdom of Judah, and she is a lot like Jezebel (who was just killed in the last chapter). Both were evil power-obsessed queens, and the similarity highlights that Judah is becoming like their evil counterpart to the north. Athaliah is killing all her grandchildren; this is to prevent them taking their rightful place on the throne. Joash (or Jehoash) is hidden away. Athaliah meets a violent end much like her beginning. Joash becomes a king who is relatively positive at the beginning. He begins ruling at 7 years old, and restores the temple which has been neglected. But he doesn't destroy the high places meaning he didn't remove the places of idol worship, and he gives the sacred items in the temple to the king of Syria (which were not his to give). Ultimately he dies like his grandma. </p>
        <p>Romans 1: The book of Romans may be Paul’s most detailed work. In it, he is giving a detailed explanation of the Gospel to the Jewish and Gentile Christ-followers in Rome. The main idea of the book of Romans is found in verse 16. Paul claims the Gospel is the power of God and salvation for all who believe (first for the Jewish Christian then for the Gentile Christian… Paul will unpack this later in the letter). He will then dissect this throughout the rest of the book. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun12">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?162</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 13</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.13.NIV">2 Kings 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.14.NIV">2 Kings 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.4-5.NIV">Proverbs 17:4-5</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 13-14: Today we will read about two Israelite kings. Remember all Israelite kings are wicked, and the author is building to a tragic end that will happen in the next few chapters. Jehoash is king in Israel (not to be confused with the Jehoash of Judah that we just read about. They have the same name... which is super confusing). But, they are two different kings. Afterwards, we'll read about Elisha’s death. This marks a change in the book, Israel (the northern kingdom) will not repent; they're on a downward spiral. Therefore, exile and captivity are immanent for Israel. But notice in the midst of this the author gives a glimpse that God is compassionate. </p>
        <p>Proverbs 17:4-5: A powerful line in verse 5 reminds us that God cares about the poor and unfortunate. In the ancient world, the poor were viewed as cursed by God, but this proverb reminds us that God cares about the poor and when we speak ill of or mistreat the unfortunate, we are not demonstrating God’s heart. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun13">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?163</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 14</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.15.NIV">2 Kings 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.16.NIV">2 Kings 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.6.NIV">Proverbs 17:6</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 15-16 – Today, we return to reading about a king in the southern kingdom of Judah along with multiple kings in the northern kingdom of Israel.  Remember that when a king does not destroy the high places, it means they're condoning idolatry and all that comes with it (immorality, sacrifices, etc.). We read about Azariah (also known as Uzziah) who rules in the time of the prophet Isaiah. As you read, notice that in the reign of one king in Judah, you have many kings in Israel. This is showing the power struggle, greed, idolatry, and wickedness of the northern kingdom. As you read, you feel that Israel is becoming worse and worse. It's all building to their impending captivity. </p>
        <p>Proverbs 17:6 – In the ancient world life expectancy was not long at all. Grandchildren were seen as a “crown” because generally speaking it shows a life of wise decisions and a raised family that made wise decisions. Ultimately it is a powerful reminder to raise our families in wisdom as they become a legacy for us.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun14">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?164</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 15</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.17.NIV">2 Kings 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.18.NIV">2 Kings 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.78.40-55.NIV">Psalm 78:40-55</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.7-8.NIV">Proverbs 17:7-8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.2.NIV">Romans 2</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 17-18: Today we read about the end of the northern kingdom of Israel brought about by the empire of Assyria. Assyria invaded and destroyed the northern kingdom around 722 BC, and then they carried the Israelites away from the land. The author wants to highlight that this is from God. In the ancient world, the view was when one country defeats another it means the winning country’s god defeated the losing country’s god. The author of 2 Kings is highlighting that God did not lose, He allowed this and has an ultimate plan beyond this. Judah will go into exile a little over a century later.</p>
        <p>Romans 2: In order for Paul to display the necessity of the Gospel, Paul must first prove humanity’s sin. When Paul speaks of boasting in the Law, he is trying to prove the Jewish people are no better off because of the Law. The Law if anything proves their sin even more so. Therefore, both the Jewish people and the Gentiles need a savior.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun15">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?165</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 16</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.19.NIV">2 Kings 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.20.NIV">2 Kings 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.78.56-72.NIV">Psalm 78:56-72</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.9-11.NIV">Proverbs 17:9-11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.3.NIV">Romans 3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 20: Hezekiah's error in showing the king of Babylon all of the treasures in the storehouses is problematic because Hezekiah is hoping to gain security through friendship with the king of Babylon. God is displeased with Hezekiah's lack of discreteness, and does not hold back in prophesying against the nation of Judah for Hezekiah's sin. </p>
        <p>Proverbs 17:9: Letting go of offenses can be some of the most difficult work we do, but when we see how it fosters and promotes love, it is always worth the sacrifice.</p>
        <p>Romans 3: In verses 10-18 Paul quotes several verses from the Old Testament. If you take the time to look them up, you'll see that they are not word for word quotations. New Testament writers like Paul would at times combine or adapt Scripture to build their argument. Under the inspiration of the Holy Spirit as he wrote, Paul is showing how in many different places in Scripture, especially the Psalms, it is evident that all people are sinners.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun16">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?166</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 17</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.21.NIV">2 Kings 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.22.NIV">2 Kings 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.79.NIV">Psalm 79</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.12-13.NIV">Proverbs 17:12-13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.4.NIV">Romans 4</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 21-22: Perhaps no greater contrast exists in the book of kings than that of Manasseh and Josiah. Manasseh's sins were great and deeply offensive in the eyes of the Lord. Over and over throughout the book, the author will refer to Manasseh's sins. In contrast, his grandson Josiah, wisely listens and responds to God's Law. God deals mercifully with Josiah because of Josiah's repentance, but God still intends to judge the country of Judah for their sins.</p>
        <p>Romans 4: Paul continues to build his case that we are saved through faith, not through our good works. Abraham was celebrated by the Jewish people for his faithfulness to God, and Paul is pointing out that it was Abraham's faith that pleased God.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun17">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?167</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 18</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/0SVTl4Xa5fY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.23.NIV">2 Kings 23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.24.NIV">2 Kings 24</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.80.NIV">Psalm 80</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.14-15.NIV">Proverbs 17:14-15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.5.NIV">Romans 5</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 24: The Babylonians are sent by the Lord to bring judgement on Judah. The people of Judah are exiled in three different waves, the first one being in 2 Kings 24:12-17. </p>
        <p>Psalm 80: The reference to "Ephraim, Benjamin, and Manasseh," might be in reference to the nation of Israel during the attack of the Assyrians. These were the tribes located in the northern part of Israel. This psalmist uses a vine metaphor for the nation of Israel, reminding God of the vine He planted and chose.</p>
        <p>Romans 5: Notice as you read how many times Paul writes, "how much more"- Paul could not emphasize enough how great of a position in life we now have because of Jesus' sacrifice.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun18">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?168</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 19</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/2KI.25.NIV">2 Kings 25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.81.NIV">Psalm 81</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.16.NIV">Proverbs 17:16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.6.NIV">Romans 6</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>2 Kings 25: Zedekiah follows in Jehoiakim's footsteps and tries to rebel against Babylon, this time causing Babylon to destroy the entire city of Jerusalem. The temple is destroyed by fire, and the second wave of people are taken into exile. </p>
        <p>Psalm 81: This psalm would most likely be sung at the New Moon festival or called the Feast of Tabernacles. It is a psalm full of reminders about Israel's history and God's commands and promises.</p>
        <p>Romans 6: In chapters 6-8, Paul is going to outline the reality of the Christian life in the pursuit to overcome sin and live righteously, by being empowered by the Holy Spirit. In chapter 6, he uses the analogy of being a slave and serving a master. Christians are "slaves to righteousness,"  meaning they willingly serve Christ and honor Him as their master. Prior to serving Christ, we had no choice but to be a slave to sin.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun19">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?169</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 20</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe src="https://youtube.com/embed/HR7xaHv3Ias" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer"; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; allowfullscreen> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.1.NIV">1 Chronicles 1</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.2.NIV">1 Chronicles 2</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.17-18.NIV">Proverbs 17:17-18</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 1: Through the first nine chapters of 1 Chronicles, we will be reading through the genealogies. Genealogies served several purposes, but one of the most important is that they legitimized the different family lines that existed through the time of the exile. Once the Israelites are no longer exiles, they want to rebuild the temple (requiring priests, families descending from Aaron), and they will want to follow the Davidic royal line.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 17:17: One of the best biblical examples of a friend loving at all times is the story of David and Jonathan. Their mutual love and commitment to each other is shown throughout both of their lives.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun20">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?170</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 21</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.3.NIV">1 Chronicles 3</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.4.NIV">1 Chronicles 4</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.19-21.NIV">Proverbs 17:19-21</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 4: It can feel tedious to continue to read through genealogies, but it is fascinating to see the times where the author adds short anecdotes along with peoples' names. In 4:10 Jabez's story stands out because he was a man who cried out to God, and God answered him. In 4:40 the author describes the land that the Simeonites inhabited in detail, a sign of blessing. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun21">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?171</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 22</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.5.NIV">1 Chronicles 5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.6.NIV">1 Chronicles 6</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.82.NIV">Psalm 82</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.22.NIV">Provebs 17:22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.7.NIV">Romans 7</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 82: God's expectations of leaders is that they would care for the poor and marginalized. Those who are unwilling to care for the disadvantaged "know nothing, understand nothing, and walk in darkness." </p>
        <p>Romans 7: Paul explains how the Old Testament law is not sinful itself, but instead reveals sin in the lives and hearts of people. Later we see Paul's wrestle with sin. His experience is like every Christian- doing what we know is sinful, and not doing what we know is good. Verses 24 and 25 provide the answer to this great conundrum: Jesus Christ has saved us from this body of death. </p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun22">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?172</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 23</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.7.NIV">1 Chronicles 7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.8.NIV">1 Chronicles 8</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.83.NIV">Psalm 83</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.23.NIV">Proverbs 17:23</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.8.NIV">Romans 8</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 83: This Psalm brings up several of Israel's enemies. Verse 9 is referring to events that happened during the time when Israel had judges. The stories are referring to when God used two different judges, Samson and Barak.</p>
        <p>Romans 8: Paul goes on to explain how it is that Christians live lives controlled by the Holy Spirit. In verse 15, Paul says through the Holy Spirit we can cry out, "Abba, Father." This is an intimate name of which to call God, and shows just how close of a relationship God desires to have with each of His children.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun23">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?173</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 24</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.9.NIV">1 Chronicles 9</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.10.NIV">1 Chronicles 10</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.84.NIV">Psalm 84</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.24-25.NIV">Proverbs 17:24-25</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.9.NIV">Romans 9</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 84: Valley of Baca means a "place of weeping." As the pilgrims make their way to worship God, even the painful places in life can be full of refreshment.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 17:24 One of the differences between the foolish and the wise is where their focus lies. The fool looks to anything and everything around the world, while the wise person fixes their eyes on wisdom only, constantly seeking it out.</p>
        <p>Romans 9: Paul now transitions in chapters 9-11 to describe God's heart and ways with the people of Israel. God had chosen Israel as His special people, but because of their unbelief, He has made a way for Gentiles to be His own people.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun24">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?174</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 25</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.11.NIV">1 Chronicles 11</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.12.NIV">1 Chronicles 12</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.85.NIV">Psalm 85</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.26.NIV">Proverbs 17:26</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.10.NIV">Romans 10</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 11-12: The rest of 1 Chronicles will follow the kingship of David. The author's purpose is to show David as an image of the Messianic King to come, so he uses positive stories from David's life to reinforce this picture. </p>
        <p>Romans 10: Paul deeply loved and was concerned for the salvation of his fellow Israelites. His argument builds out of that desire for them to understand their error and accept Christ as Savior. Filled with lots of quotations, Paul continues to use Scripture and sayings of the time to point to Christ as the answer. The chapter ends with Isaiah's words from the past showing how God has continued to reach towards Israel despite their rejection of Him.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun25">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?175</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 26</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.13.NIV">1 Chronicles 13</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.14.NIV">1 Chronicles 14</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.86.NIV">Psalm 86</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.17.27-28.NIV">Proverbs 17:27-28</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.11.NIV">Romans 11</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 86: In David's time of pain and desperation, notice how many times he reflects on Who God is and turns his attention and thoughts back to God. David is honest about his pain and difficult situation, but he is also mindful of how great God is.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 17:27-28 The author is a proponent of "less is more" when it comes to words. "Even a fool is thought wise if he keeps silent..." is a sharp reminder that anyone has the opportunity to be thought of as wise, just so long as they watch their mouth.</p>
        <p>Romans 11: Paul ends this section about the condition of Israel by reminding his audience that God will have mercy on the people of Israel, just as He had mercy on the Gentiles. The doxology is Paul's worship of the God Who so brilliantly crafted a plan for both the Jews and the Gentiles to be saved.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun26">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?176</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 27</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.15.NIV">1 Chronicles 15</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.16.NIV">1 Chronicles 16</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.1.NIV">Proverbs 18:1</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 15: In the story of the ark being brought to Jerusalem, notice how King David is the one orchestrating so much of the celebration. The author of Chronicles is showing how a king ought to lead his people in worshipping God. David's obedience in bringing the ark of God into Jerusalem is momentous, and David celebrates this moment to the full. </p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 16: David's Psalm of Thanks has similar content to three different Psalms: Psalm 105, Psalm 96, and Psalm 106. The author of Chronicles is writing for an audience that is coming out of exile, so these Psalms of remembering all that God has done and promised would have been very special to them.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun27">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?177</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 28</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.17.NIV">1 Chronicles 17</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.18.NIV">1 Chronicles 18</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.2-3.NIV">Proverbs 18:2-3</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>1 Chronicles 17: The words found in 17:11-14 were referencing David's son Solomon and the establishment of the Davidic royal line, however Mark, Luke, and the author of Hebrews show how Jesus is the fulfillment of these words. </p>
        <p>Proverbs 18:2: A caution that anytime we stop listening and begin only thinking about sharing our own idea, we are heading down the path of foolishness.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun28">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?178</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 29</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.19.NIV">1 Chronicles 19</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.20.NIV">1 Chronicles 20</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.87.NIV">Psalm 87</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.4-5.NIV">Proverbs 18:4-5</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.12.NIV">Romans 12</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 87: Verse 4 records several nations that are meant to represent Gentiles as a whole. The psalmist prophecies of a day where outsider nations will gather in Jerusalem because they too are God's people.</p>
        <p>Proverbs 18:4: The "bubbling brook" is imagery for a source of refreshment. Not only are wise words profound, they are also good for the soul and life-giving.</p>
        <p>Romans 12: This chapter begins with "Therefore," which is the sum of the entire eleven chapters beforehand. The theology laid out previously is what informs and empowers the kind of living God calls for believers to live out. Chapters 12-15 are full of practical application for living out salvation everyday.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun29">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?179</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>June 30</title>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[ <hr>
        <iframe frameborder="0" allowfullscreen height="1"> </iframe>
        <br>
        <br>
        <ul>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.21.NIV">1 Chronicles 21</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/1CH.22.NIV">1 Chronicles 22</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PSA.88.NIV">Psalm 88</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/PRO.18.6-7.NIV">Proverbs 18:6-7</a></li>
          <li><a href="https://bible.com/en/bible/111/ROM.13.NIV">Romans 13</a></li>
        </ul>
        <p>Notes on what you will read today:</p>
        <p>Psalm 88: This is one of the darkest psalms, with hardly any words of hope. The first verse offers the only sense of faith and comfort, "O LORD, the God who saves me..." The psalmist was not afraid to pour out his grievances and pain before the God who he knew saves.</p>
        <p>Romans 13: Paul's original audience at the time may have been tempted to not submit to authorities and instead claim to only follow Christ. This is not how Christians are to interact with their governmental leaders. Paul calls Christians to submit and says that all authority in life has been established by God.</p>

        <img src="https://bible.newheights.org/1.png?Jun30">
      ]]>
    </description>
    <link>https://newheights.org/?180</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">7bd204c6-1655-4c27-aeee-53f933c5395f</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 16:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
  </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
